It can't be.
Atri's the girl from eight years ago?
No! She can't be!
That girl was calmer, more mature!
She wasn't anything like this thing!
There, there. It's okay.
Crap. She's already invading my memories.
All because she had to go and say something stupid!
Hey. Atri.
What is it?
Wake up. We need to talk.
It's the middle of the night.
I told you, I'm low-voltage...
Hey! Atri!
Did you have a bad dream? It's okay.
No...
Nooooo!
Just admit it.
Why should I? It's totally unrealistic.
I met that girl eight whole years ago.
Oh, it's perfectly realistic.
She's a Humanoid, so her appearance wouldn't change.
Okay, lookin' good.
Listen to me!
First of all, Atri matches the girl's physical description with her red eyes and smooth hair.
That's just a coincidence.
Second of all, you met her when you were nine,
and if she looked about fourteen at the time,
that lines up with how Atri looks now.
That's just because Humanoids are designed to look like young humans.
Third of all, she was being kept with Grandma Nonko's stuff,
she remembered the song she sang when you first met,
and to top it all off, she hits you with the "It's been so long, Natsuki-san."
It's lookin' pretty hard to deny at this point.
Natsu-kun actually lost an argument...
To freakin' Ryuuji, even.
Shut it!
It's just not possible. Atri can't be that girl!
Natsuki-san! How could you!?
Why didn't you wake me up?
I did, but you weren't having it.
Waking people up
involves continuing until they're well and truly awake!
If they go back to sleep, it doesn't count!
Whatever, Webster.
This wouldn't have happened if you didn't wake me at such a bizarre hour!
You were muttering about who-knows-what until the crack of dawn!
He was?
Yes, something about proving that something wasn't me...
Living rent-free in your head, huh?
Of course she is! She's the girl who saved my damn life!
And this rusty water heater ain't it, chief!
Do you never learn? Eat my double rocket punch!
I dunno, I think it's touching.
Touching?
Isn't it?
You've been apart for so long, but look at you now! You're best friends!
Look, I'm telling you, it's nothing but wishful speculation...
But she was like, "It's been so long, Natsuki-san," right?
S-So it seems...
Oh yeah!
I bet that means you've remembered Natsu-kun's grandma's orders, right?
And how you ended up in that capsule, too.
Oh. Yeah, you're right!
Maybe if we knew that, we could prove she's not the girl I met!
How about it?
But of course!
B-Because I have the highest specs in town!
Really?
Allow me to load the relevant data.
Just one moment!
Um...
Um... Umm... Ummm...
Ummmm, ummmmm...
Aum...
King of the waffle irons, right here.
How rude!
I'm built to resemble a woman, I'll have you know!
You should be calling me a queen, not a king!
That's the issue?
Well, there you have it. That "it's been so long" was just random nonsense.
I'm sure she only knew the song 'cause she'd happened to hear it somewhere else.
It was on top of a cliff.
You were sitting in a wheelchair,
and it looked like you were going to roll up to the cliff's edge at any moment.
Singing the song brought that memory to the surface.
I can't remember anything else, but...
I think we've got an open-and-shut case here.
Geronimo!
Whoa...
I hate to admit it, but at this stage,
I might just have to face the facts...
Whatcha writing?
Don't peek at my stuff!
Is it about Atri?
I mean--well, yeah.
You think she might have emotions, right?
How do you know that?
Minamo told me. Wanted to know what I think.
What do you think?
I think it's possible.
Despite losing her memories, she's still acting completely devoted to you,
and I can't deny the possibility that real emotions might have a hand in that.
But if she does have emotions, you'd better think about how to control her.
Control her?
Our hearts and emotions are what make us humans special.
But at the same time,
our hearts and emotions can also make us do some very stupid things.
Just as emotions give rise to love and affection,
they can just as easily produce crime and violence.
And the biggest problem of all is that those urges will trump any amount of logic.
Hence why Humanoids with emotions are considered dangerous.
You'd better determine whether she really does have emotions.
For your own good.
That said, though...
How do I check for that?
Today, Minamo taught me how to make hamburg steak!
She did?
Yes! She's teaching me how to cook as part of an after-school club.
I'll make you some for dinner!
Sure you're up to it?
With specs like mine, anything's possible!
Minamo even told me I'm a fast learner!
Now I'm ready to go!
You learn that from Minamo, too?
Did I get it wrong?
This is how you really do it.
Oh!
Are you happy?
Yes!
What was that for!?
Are you mad?
What's your problem!? Harrumph!
You could call that emotion, I guess,
but it's entirely possible her AI
is just serving up believable reactions to specific situations...
In which case...
What's gotten into you? You're acting extra weird today.
Atri.
Yes? What is it?
Look me in the eye.
Aye aye.
I love you.
Natsuki-san?
I mean it.
Or rather, if I did, what would you think?
I...
I love you too, Natsuki-san!
You do?
Yes! I love you veeery much!
Yeah, not what I meant.
It's not?
You know what? Never mind. Let's get going.
He was disappointed?
Yes...
You sure you didn't make him mad somehow?
He asked me if I love him, so I said I do...
I never can tell what's going through his head...
So that's your angle, huh?
What should I do?
Well, I think you've got the right approach,
but she's lacking in the knowledge department.
Knowledge?
Without a good understanding of emotions,
she's not gonna react, whether she has any or not.
Let me handle this.
Okay, class, time to get started!
Today, we're gonna cancel math and have a special health class.
Boys, you go to the roof. Girls, you're staying here.
What? We're splitting up?
Sorry, kiddo. It's a real important class for the girls.
Go hang out with Natsuki-sensei, and I'll come get you when we're done.
Let's go.
Fine...
Okay, let's get started.
Today, we're learning about the difference between "like" and "love."
Like and love?
Let's see... Oh, is this it?
This will tell us about the "love" Catherine was talking about?
I think so.
I don't really get it either,
but she says it's different from when you say you love curry or roller coasters or whatever.
Really, now...
So this is...
Love...
Yeah. It says the big difference is whether your heart's in it.
And how actions speak louder than words.
Like, what do you want Natsuki-sensei to do?
Well...
I want him to be happy!
I want him to feel like I'm being useful.
All done!
This looks good.
Doesn't it? Believe it or not, I've got some impressive specs inside me!
As long as I learn the proper procedure, I can perform to the fullest extent of my abilities!
Not so fast.
I haven't tasted it yet.
Don't worry! Have you ever known me to make a mistake?
Looks like you're losing some of your more recent memories, too.
It's great!
Well? Is it tasty?
Is this a classic case of "tasty equals happy," Natsuki-san!?
I can't say I'm thrilled by that smug look on your face,
but yes, it's pretty good.
Isn't it?
Still, how'd she get this good this fast?
Natsuki-san!
Do you have any plans tomorrow?
Not really, no. Why do you ask?
Would you like to go out with me?
Natsuki-san! Time's a-wasting!
Don't run off like that.
I can't keep up with you.
Oh, that's right!
Hop on! I'll be your legs and carry you.
I don't think so. Besides, you're already carrying a backpack.
Oh, I forgot!
What's in it?
That's a secret.
Eh, whatever. So where are we going?
Uh, apparently shopping is one of the basics.
What's that paper?
Secret!
You sure have a lot of those.
But whatever.
Looking for anything in particular?
No, not as such.
But we're coming here anyway?
Apparently the important thing is to go together.
Gotcha...
Catherine or Minamo must've put her up to this.
Talk about keeping it simple.
So he packed up and bolted, huh?
Is something in there?
No.
They're all alone.
Now's our chance to-
No.
If we make a scene, the professor will lose face again.
With the situation this out of hand, we have to start by proving that logic and reality are on our side.
Here you go!
It smells great!
How's it taste?
Sour! But also nice and sweet!
You can have mine too, if you want.
Huh? You're being so nice today...
Well, sure. It's a date.
Hwuh!?
Then you can have a bite, too!
Huh?
It's a date!
Now that's sour! But I like it.
Tasty equals happy, right?
Sure does.
Can we go look at shoes now?
But of course!
I see they have some new ones in stock!
Well, it's been a while since we came here.
Which shoes do you want?
They're not for me--they're for you.
Your current shoes are pretty beat-up, right?
For me?
What do you think of these ones? Looks like just the right size to me.
Yup. Nice and summery, don't you think?
But they're rather lacking in functionality.
I'm supposed to be supporting you, so functionality is very important!
For instance...
Look at these!
Uh, those look even harder to walk in.
But they'll reduce the height gap between us.
I'll get closer to you!
Atri...
I-I'd say that makes them very functional, wouldn't you?
H-How do I look?
Great.
It feels like I'm seeing a whole new world!
Yeah. Like...
You look grown-up.
Is that bad?
I mean, uh, can you walk okay?
Yes!
What are these things!?
Who in their right mind would design shoes so utterly bereft of functionality?
Well, there's fashion, aesthetics...
Anyway, are you sure you're okay with those?
Yes! You picked them out just for me!
What's that?
Lunch!
Whoa, that looks really good!
All I've learned from Minamo is hamburg steak,
so I'm afraid this will be a repeat of last night's dinner...
Oh, that's okay.
I'm impressed you got them looking this good with so little practice.
Your happiness is a big motivator!
I know! I hereby dub these sandwiches The Miracle of Natsuki-san!
What kind of a name is that? Eh, whatever.
Don't mind if I do.
Are you okay, Natsuki-san?
It's nothing.
That doesn't look like nothing! You're crying!
It's, uh, so good it threw me for a loop, that's all.
Robo-vision!
Robo-analysis!
Aah! I used too much mustard!
No, uh, it's just right. Nice and... stimulating. Yeah.
Here I wanted to get them absolutely perfect so I could make you happy...
Nah, it's better if they're not perfect.
Huh?
Makes it easier to feel the heart in 'em.
My heart, you mean?
Yeah.
You've changed quite a bit.
I was kinda hoping for a happier response.
Happy?
Yeah. See, I think you might have a real heart inside you.
What do you think?
Do you think you have a heart?
You think I do, right?
It would make you happy if I did, right?
I think... I do.
Really?
I've never been an actual human, so I can't say for sure,
but I think these urges, this happiness and sadness,
love and hate,
exist in me more strongly than can be explained as academic knowledge.
Really? You really think so!?
Yes!
It's nice and cold!
Careful, now. It's pretty deep around here.
Oh! Look, a crab!
Sure that's not a hermit crab?
Is it?
Ha! You fell for it!
What was that for!?
Whoa! Wait!
I think not! Taste your punishment for tricking me!
If you think I'll let a toaster get the best of me, you've got another thing coming!
So you add to your crimes, do you!?
You'll pay for that!
Take this!
Hey! Stop it, toaster!
Will you ever learn your lesson!?
Why are you laughing?
I wonder that myself, actually.
Are you really that happy that I have a heart?
I guess I am.
Why?
Huh?
Why does it make you happy that I have a heart?
Because...
Because?
Atri...