The capsule told me...
about Nonko's final order.
Eden?
That's where you're supposed to go?
Yes.
The capsule is set up so that when it runs out of battery,
it installs that order in me.
And then I could spring into action.
Then...
But we woke you up early and took you out of the capsule.
That's why you didn't remember the order!
But why go to all that trouble?
Probably to prevent information leaks.
This way, if someone took the unconscious Atri out of the capsule and extracted her data,
they'd never know about this order.
Grandma was always the cautious type.
Yes. In short...
It's not my fault I couldn't remember!
Well, I mean...
But nooo, you had to shower me in hate speech every chance you got!
Well, too bad! I really am high-spec!
I'm the perfect Humanoid!
Someone sure is smug...
Must've been holding it in for a while.
Atri...
So where is this "Eden" thing?
Oh, that's simple.
That way!
That way?
That's all?
Yes.
It should be that way...
What even is "Eden," anyway?
No idea.
Do you know the exact coordinates?
Nope.
What are you supposed to do when you get there?
It's a mystery, isn't it?
Hey, Natsu. Is it just me, or...
Toaster.
Super revolving rocket punch!
Whole lotta nothing.
I'm not seeing anything, either.
You sure it's there?
All I know is that I have to go there...
Isn't it awfully, you know, incomplete for an order?
How's she supposed to follow it if she has no idea what to do?
Knowing my grandma, it's possible.
Not only was she super cautious, she also didn't have an ounce of trust in anybody.
Really?
Yeah.
"The only person you can trust is yourself."
She used to say that a lot.
It's because of my leg!
If it weren't for my leg, I could've gone on the rocket!
Hah! Blaming that old thing, are you?
Grow a spine, lad!
What was I supposed to do?!
Think for yourself.
If you can't do that, then keep up your "woe is me" act forever
instead of actually accomplishing something.
That's awful...
Well, she was able to make it on her own. She was strong enough.
So you think Eden is real, huh?
Yeah. There's no way she wouldn't see something like this through.
Be careful out there!
Let us know if you find it!
Yeah! See you later!
Welp, let's get going and start class.
Eden...
What's up, Ririka?
Haven't we seen that word somewhere?
I dunno.
The Amaterasu Project was established to investigate the cause of the rising sea levels,
and the launch of its weather satellite is only one week away.
The government has announced that the launch will proceed according to schedule.
Who'da thunk we'd be this clueless, huh?
We just have to search the old-fashioned way.
We've only got so much fuel, though.
We can't just run around aimlessly.
How about it? You got some kind of Eden-dar that'll tell us if we're getting warmer?
No, nothing...
Any idea of how big it is?
No.
Could it be underwater?
Maybe.
We don't got any decent sonar on this thing.
We're gonna need some kind of clue.
I'll take a look!
Huh? Hey!
Atri?
Don't be so hard on her. It really gets to her.
No, uh, I didn't mean it like that...
Do you think the professor could just be messing with her?
No. She had an awful personality,
but she was a scientist at heart.
She wouldn't leave behind an unsolvable problem.
Natsuki, big news! I found it!
Really?!
Yeah! A crab!
Huh?! Don't crabs make you happy?!
Well, it's better than nothing, I guess...
Exactly! Crabs are tasty!
And tasty equals happy!
Looks awfully chipper to me.
Maybe we should go down to the lab again...
Heeey!
Natsuki-sensei!
We figured out what Eden is.
Ririka found it!
Huh?
I bet this is it. Look!
She found it when she was trying to learn about Atri!
Professor Yachigusa's your grandma, right?
They did an interview with her in this newspaper!
"In preparation for the inevitable rising sea levels..."
Huh? Hey, Natsu...
That day, the wind was blowing in this direction.
So the ship would've gotten carried this way...
Natsu?
What's gotten into you?
I think I've got it.
I know where Eden is.
Really?!
It was foggy back then.
That would mean Eden must be...
Let's check it out.
Right now?
You sure?
Yeah.
I want some closure here, too. Let's do this thing.
We're coming, too!
School's out for the day.
But-
Ms. Hana said we could go!
Okay.
I'm not seeing anything.
Yeah.
Nothing here, either.
Ready to head to the next place?
Yeah.
We still couldn't find it, huh?
Look, are we sure it really exists?
Atri.
Why can't we find it?
Here I thought I could finally follow my order...
It's not your fault.
Fog...
Looks like it.
Should we call it a day for searching with the naked eye?
There was fog back then, too...
We're going underwater? Now?
Yeah. Something's fishy about this fog.
Localized fog isn't a thing this far out at sea.
Huh?
Grandma's generating it artificially.
To hide Eden.
If I'm right about this...
It has to be here.
Natsuki!
I knew it!
An underwater cable, though? There must be tons of the things.
Yeah.
But there should hardly be any running from the island through this part of the sea.
Then if you follow that cable...
Yeah.
What's wrong?
No clue. We just got caught in a strong current!
Is this an ocean current?
Let's surface. I'll go myself!
No. I bet this is another of Grandma's tricks.
"You want to get close? You'll have to work for it."
Make your own decisions and solve your own problems.
No hesitation, no regrets.
That's the most efficient way.
Hold on tight.
Huh?
Sorry for everything I put you through.
Here goes!
Natsuki!
Atri?
What the...
Atri!
My leg...
Is this...
Could this be...
Eden?
Is this Eden?
She made something this huge?
A real...
bug? No,
this one's a robot.
She must've filtered water to create a habitable environment
and made robots to provide what she needed
to make this island capable of supporting an ecosystem.
Holy crap, Grandma...
I don't have time.
Yeah, I'll say.
Atri.
Natsuki...
You okay?
Is it morning or evening right now?
Looks like morning.
Then good morning.
Yeah. Morning.
Is this Eden?
Yeah, I think so.
It's an artificial island running on wave power, built to support human life.
What's this?
They must be reacting to you.
The whole island's been waiting for you to arrive.
Want some?
Of course not!
Huh?
I should be the one offering it to you!
Come on, what's the harm?
You're not a housework robot anymore.
Then what am I?
Sour!
But it's tasty.
Soursty!
You can just be you.
Go wherever you want, just like an ordinary human.
You can talk about whatever you want, and you can do whatever you want, too.
Whatever I want...
Yeah. Anything come to mind?
I don't know.
If I had to say...
Yeah?
Um, can I go into baby mode for a little while?
Baby mode?
When you held me, I was stable.
That's called relief.
It means your heart's at ease.
Yes...
You're cold.
I'm in low-power mode, so my body temperature has fallen.
But I can feel yours.
Yeah?
Are you relieved, Natsuki?
Yeah.
Okay, that's enough.
Why? You're still cold.
It's fine!
My body temperature has no bearing on my functionality.
Where's this coming from?
It was your idea.
It's embarrassing!
Wh-What's so funny?!
Oh, nothing.
You're just cute!
C-Cuuuuuu...
Hey, what's...
I hereby forbid you from saying that!
Why?
Because it disturbs my functionality!
Now let's go!
Ohhh...
Sorry.
I-It's fine. I'm your leg!
Whoa...
Are these all plants?
Yeah.
She's automated food production so nobody'll go hungry.
You know, they laughed her out of academia
for worrying about rising sea levels.
And ever since, she was preparing this all by herself, behind everybody's backs.
This facility is where she generates electricity and distributes it through the island
to make this place self-sustaining.
Look...
I think we've found the finish line.
It looks just like the capsule I was sleeping in.
Yeah.
Am I supposed to get in here?
Probably.
Wait.
What's this system connected to?
Natsuki?
We're leaving.
Huh?
We're done here. Let's go!
Huh? But-
Running away again?
Nonko! You were alive?
No.
That's an AI hologram she created.
Don't you realize this is your only choice?
You have to get in this capsule.
In this...
Yeah. She wants you to get in there and be this island's administrator.
She wants to build you into the mainframe!
Well, screw that!
Atri's finally become conscious of her emotions!
And you want to lock her up in here?!
Oh, I'm being unreasonable, am I?
I gave this poor girl a purpose and built a home for her.
Feel free to thank me.
A purpose...
I'll build a home for her.
You?
Oh, you're funny.
Here, let me investigate the situation the world's in.
Just how I predicted. Of course.
It's suffered catastrophic damage from the rising sea levels.
Society's in no state to develop Humanoids.
And she's under recall, at that.
Her manufacturer doesn't even exist anymore.
How do you plan on caring for her, hmm?
I'll go back to the Academy and learn about Humanoids.
And then...
You think you have time for that?
You don't even know how much time she has left.
Huh?
45 days from the moment she wakes up.
If she doesn't enter this capsule during that time,
a program I installed will erase her memories.
This place needs to remain secret, after all.
Well, well. Today's the 42nd day.
Certainly took you long enough.
Only three days left!
I'll say it one more time.
She needs to do this for herself, and for the future of humanity.
I'll let you think about it from here.
Natsuki?
Let's go.
Let's go, Atri! That's an order!
I'm sorry.
Atri...
I'm not going anywhere.