I'll be your leg, Master!
What are you...
It's a humanoid's job to serve their master!
You can't run or jump well, right?
You can let me handle that!
What do you mean by-
Uh-
You have nothing to worry about!
I'm stronger than I look!
Huh?
Wh-Whoa!
What are you doing?
Wait!
Watch this! I can jump to the boat at the end of the pier with relative ease!
Atri!
Witness the power of my high specs!
Huh?
What is wrong with you?
God, I already got dumped in the ocean once. I didn't need to do it again.
Now this is curious.
Even adjusting for your approximate body weight,
I should have been able to clear that distance easily.
Oh, I know!
Have you gained weight?
Okay, you.
Then let's give it one more try!
I don't think so!
Aww...
What are you even doing here, anyway?
I told you to go with Catherine.
Yes, and I did.
Just like you ordered.
What, so you ran away?
No, Catherine did.
What?
I traveled with Catherine after we parted, but...
Argh, this is why I hate this town!
Who is that?
Debt collectors. Fuckin' persistent sons of...
Get off. We can't make this jump together.
Huh?
Get off and hide nearby.
I'll come back for you later.
Go on, get moving!
And so I came back here while still following your orders to the letter!
Booyah!
"Booyah," my left kidney.
Now I know why she was so hungry for money...
What are you doing?
Making breakfast!
When it comes to serving my master, you'll find that my high specs-
Hm?
You sure those specs are that high?
Of course they are!
Hmmmmm?
F-Fire!
Yeah, I can see that!
Master, help!
Natsu-kun, let's go to school to...
School's really fun!
No, he'll just laugh in my face...
Huh!? Oh no!
Natsu-kun! Are you okay?
Yeah. Freaking...
Hey!
Fire extinguished, sir!
Atri-chan!
Minamo!
You came back? Is everything okay?
Was there a fire?
Yes! But I handled the situation perfectly!
I don't wanna hear it.
But this sort of human error only serves to demonstrate my high specs as a humanoid...
Most humanoids can't make mistakes, even if they try!
I'm getting real sick of that.
One wrong move, and I could've ended up homeless.
Now let's go.
Where?
To sell you.
Aw, but she came back.
Exactly!
And I have an important duty to serve you!
I'm amazed you can say that after what literally just happened.
If I keep a walking, talking pile of scrap metal like you around, my days are numbered.
S-Scrap metal!?
"Scrap metal" is in violation of whatever the hell I translated that law as last week!
Take it back immediately!
Refusal to correct yourself will lead to prosecution for robot harassment!
Shut up, scrap metal!
So you double down, do you!?
This is racism! This is a clear act of racism!
Oh, I'm not discriminating against robots! Just you!
This is unforgivable, even for my master!
Taste the power of my rocket punch!
Robots can't attack humans, dingus.
Wait! Don't do it, please!
Natsu-kun!
What?
Are you really sure?
She was really important to your grandma, wasn't she?
Besides, she's just trying to help you.
That's... just because she's following her programming.
But don't you feel sorry for her?
She has that order from your grandma, doesn't she?
Yes, though the memory data is missing...
Natsu-kun...
Argh! I've met potato batteries that're more useful than you.
Arrest this man!
That statement was a clear criminal offense!
Shut your mouth!
Are you sure you're okay with this?
Aren't you the one who was worried about my grandma?
Well, yes, but...
If she really did leave her with important orders, there must be some kind of record of it.
I'll do some digging.
This isn't everything, but it's at least the stuff that was stored the most carefully.
Is there anything you remember?
No.
"Records of the Sea Level's Rise..."
"Climate Change Projections..."
"Long-term Outlook for Global Warming..."
"Rising Sea Levels and the Associated Energy Crisis..."
It's all about the rising sea levels.
She was an oceanographer. Must've been a key issue for her.
Is that why she got Atri-chan?
Ah, it's elementary.
I'm to use my powers to halt the rise of the sea.
That's the order Nonko left me with...
Really?
Three cheers for me and my high specs!
Clearly I've been blessed with the power to manipulate the seas and save the world!
And there's no time like the present!
I'll wield my awesome powers here and now!
Begone, sea!
What are you, Moses?
So do you remember anything now, or what?
Um, about that...
Then why don't we try going to school?
School?
Yeah. All the local kids gather there.
Plus, we might be able to find something about those important orders of yours!
You can come too, Natsu-kun.
School, school... There's something familiar about that...
Really?
Yes. Whatever it is, I'm sure it's important...
Uhhh...
This again?
Be quiet! I'm thinking!
Um, umm...
Did you remember something?
Yes! It's time for lunch!
That's it. Time to cash you in.
What?
Think about it for two seconds. She's a downright liability.
I can sell her for some serious money. And then...
Master, you want to sell me so you can afford a new prosthetic, right?
Is there something you need a new prosthetic in order to do?
Why do you care?
If I can accomplish your goal by acting as your leg,
would that make you happy?
That's not-
What do you mean? "That's not" what?
Shut up. I can make do on my own.
Atri-chan, do you have a second?
Huh? But-
Go. That's an order.
Will Master be okay all on his own?
Sometimes, people need to be left alone.
Really?
Oh, look, there's my house!
Ooh! What a fine specimen it is!
Here, come in. It's just me here.
You live alone in a house this big?
Yeah. My dad's this town's mayor.
But he's evacuated to the mainland. He told me to come too, but...
You didn't go?
Yeah. Natsu-kun came back, you know.
And there's so many people still left in this town...
Atri-chan, can you drink tea?
I have no need for it, but I do possess the required functionality.
I'm high-spec!
Is this really that hot?
Natsu-kun's bad with hot food,
so it's probably better to make his tea a little more lukewarm.
You know a lot about Master.
Yeah, we go way back.
You wouldn't believe how smart he is.
He even got into the Academy on the mainland.
He was like, "I'm gonna save the world."
"I'm gonna unpause the world and get things moving again."
So he studied his butt off at the Academy
and he was even considered for the crew
of a rocket for investigating climate change,
but they told him
he didn't make the cut because of his prosthetic.
He still kept trying,
but the rising sea levels led to the rocket launch getting postponed indefinitely anyway,
and all his motivation just went up in smoke.
So Master wants to get on the rocket and go to space?
Me and my high specs can be his leg and make his dream come true!
Oh, even the highest specs in the world won't help you there.
Does that mean he would be better off selling me and buying a new prosthetic?
No, it's okay. I don't think he'll sell you.
Why do you say that? I fail to see the logic in that.
Hmm...
It's hard to say, but I think he likes you.
He does?
Yeah. So don't talk about the future too much - just stick by him, okay?
That alone will be a huge weight off his shoulders!
Just being with him will help him...
I don't get it...
Humans sure are full of mysteries.
I'm home, Master!
Help...
Shouting in your sleep is quite an impressive feat.
Are your brain functions experiencing an error?
Atri...
Your brain might be in need of repairs.
If you can do that, go for it.
Let me wipe your sweat. You don't want to catch a cold.
Humans are fragile. They break down so easily.
Um, I'd like to wipe your sweat...
Don't worry about that.
You're supposed to be my leg, aren't you?
Legs don't complain.
I've updated my model.
Can I just go to sleep like this?
Of course, Master.
Enough of that. Just call me Natsuki.
Okay, Natsuki-san.
I don't care how bad a nightmare I was having.
If she remembers I showed weakness to her, I'll never live it down!
No, wait. What if that was part of the dream, too?
Aw, Natsuki-san, who knew you could be so cute?
Kill me now.
Mmm, Natsuki-san, you dirty boy...
Up and at 'em!
What was that for!?
Waking a robot up from a good night's sleep is in violation of the...
Wake up already, you glorified calculator!
That's another racist slur...
Forget everything!
Wipe everything that happened yesterday from your memory!
Master's orders!
Yesterday?
Ahaha, you mean when you hugged me passionately, went to sleep on my lap...
Aaaugh! Don't say it!
I hate to burst your bubble, but I'm incapable of intentionally deleting my memory.
I'm too high-spec for...
Hey. Hey!
How are you not a morning person? You're a robot!
I'm low voltage...
Low voltage? What's that supposed to mean?
I can't reach my back teeth.
What're you looking at me for?
It's the owner's job to perform maintenance on their robot.
And the cleaner I am, the higher I'll sell for.
Go on. Rinse your mouth.
Also, I'll forget about selling you for now.
I'm supposed to be splitting the money with Catherine, after all.
If I sell you on my own, there could be hell to pay later.
Besides,
the thought of someone seeing your memories of last night makes me wanna blow my brains out.
Mweh heh, Minamo was right on the money.
Huh?
You liiiiike me and my high specs, don't you?
What!?
You naughty boy...
You were so adorable when you held me in your arms.
Huh?
You stop that right now, or I'll erase those memories with some good old percussive maintenance!
Robot harassment! Robot harassment!
How dare you take advantage of the fact that robots can't harm humans!
I don't wanna hear it! You tried to punch me yesterday!
Now look what you've done.
My joints feel all misaligned...
You got what you deserved.
How do you figure that!?
Well, hey, it's a good thing Atri-chan's here now.
Look, the instant I work things out with Catherine, it's off to the market with her.
With her memory wiped.
Which means as long as she doesn't show up, things stay the way they are, right?
Well...
Let's go to school.
School...
Are you nervous? It's fun.
You can learn all kinds of things, you can make friends...
I understand that, but there's something about school...
Like...
Well, you won't hear me stop you.
Might finally get some peace and quiet around here.
What? You wouldn't come with me?
And what would be the point of that?
Then I won't go either!
I have to stay by your side so I can be your leg!
For the record, not once have I ever asked for that.
But a humanoid has to-
So you're saying as long as Natsu-kun comes, you'll come too, right?
I know there's nothing at school for you, Natsu-kun.
But it's the only school this town has.
If it goes away, that's it.
Is it wrong of me to want to keep it alive?
Where are we going?
Stocking up on provisions. Water, too.
Public infrastructure's in shambles,
and utilities are still out of commission.
Even the turbines don't work.
Looks like this one's starting to die on me, too...
I'll have to look for another water source.
This should still be good.
Look what I found!
Is this edible?
Junk food? Yeah, but put it back.
Huh?
There's kids around here, too.
They'll be sad if their favorite snacks are gone.
Some people only thought about themselves,
sneaking away with some stuff,
but they gave up on this place and left a long time ago.
The only people left here are the ones who don't have the money to go anywhere else.
This town's been abandoned.
See those turbines over there?
There used to be land under them.
Back then, we were connected to the mainland.
We weren't a ghost town, like we are now.
But...
it's pretty.
I think this town is very pretty.
And Minamo is rich, but she still lives here.
She could move away if she wanted to.
Well...
I'm sure some people stay here because they like it here.
Maybe even Nonko...
Maybe she wanted to save this town.
Natsuki-san!
Is that thing over there
the rocket?
Yeah.
Will it fly?
Sure.
One day, it will launch.
Huh? Isn't home this way?
Where are...
Beats me. Must've taken a wrong turn.
Ended up somewhere I've never been.
I don't have records of that sort of novel architecture in my memory banks.
Yeah? Seeing it for yourself doesn't ring any bells, huh?
Seeing it for...
Huh?
Wait, is this the school?
See you tomorrow!
That was Minamo's voice!
Minamo!
Hm? Atri-chan!
Perfect timing, Minamo.
You can start taking Atri with you from now on.
Huh? But I-
Relax. It won't be every day, but I'll come every once in a while, too.
Natsu-kun!
This is... the school?
Everything okay?
Yes.
It's nothing!