Look how fast we're going!
The wind's so refreshing!
Check out how much water we're kicking up back here!
Hold on tight and don't fall overboard!
This is the place, right?
You really think you can pull this off?
Pull what off?
Building a tidal power generator!
Nothing that says we can't, in theory.
To generate electricity, all you need to do is spin a turbine.
You can use wind power, nuclear power, tidal power, anything goes.
It's as simple as it sounds.
We're just a bunch of kids!
We've got no materials, no tools, no nothing.
That's why we're out here on this salvage mission.
And what if it blows up in your face, huh?
Then we'd learn a valuable lesson,
and we'd start thinking about a plan B.
That's how you make progress.
I'm back!
What're you wearing a swimsuit for?
Huh? Why shouldn't I?
Atri-chan said she'd be going for a dive, so I thought...
We're talking about the seafloor here.
Best leave that to the professionals.
We're gonna make electricity outta that...
All right, let's do this thing!
Hey, it's a perfect fit!
I knew Minamo-onee-chan's middle school swimsuit would be the right size!
Why does my chest feel so empty all of a sudden?
Okay, we're in position.
Now,
let's get this show on the road!
Natsu-kun! Natsu-kun, can you hear me?
Yeah, I just got here.
Where's that?
It's, uh...
The Kannon-mae intersection, it looks like.
Atri, you there?
Don't scare me like that!
How's it look? Think you can do it?
Look, I told you I wouldn't be able to hear you.
What is it?
I think that's the old Japanese bakery over there.
Oh, I remember that place! My mom bought me cakes from there all the time.
Ryuu-chan, you liked yours with custard, right?
You find my family's factory yet, or what?
Yeah, it's right up ahead.
"Nojima Machinery."
Your last name's Nojima?
Oh, shut up!
The resin's in the back warehouse, right?
I told you, I can't hear you!
[unintelligible robot noises]
No, we are not taking him home!
Look, if Ryuuji's right,
there should be drums of resin in that warehouse.
I swear...
Still, I never expected that.
She vaulted the uncanny valley like it was nothing.
The uncanny valley?
It's a phenomenon where robots that imperfectly mimic human expressions,
actually cause people to feel revulsion instead.
It's considered one of the biggest challenges in Humanoid research and development.
But it's not a problem for Atri-chan?
Well... guess that goes to show just how lifelike she is.
Crabs!
That's right! I took back as many as I could!
What's a robot like you so happy about?
Crabs are tasty! And tasty things make me happy!
Good work out there!
Huh? Is that a baking tray?
Yeah. Looked usable enough.
Think you can rustle up the ingredients?
I'm sure the kids would love a sweet treat.
Natsu-kun!
Flour, eggs, and sweet bean paste should be all we need, right?
I think I can manage that!
So what about the resin? That's what we came here for in the first place.
No problems there.
The lids were all on tight, and there weren't any leaks.
I think we're in business.
For real?
I also grabbed some useful-looking tools from the factory.
Mind checking 'em out for me?
Huh?
S-Sure. Guess I could do that much...
All right, boys and girls,
once we get back to school, we're having ourselves a barbecue!
Really?
We're feasting on crab tonight!
This is great!
You can say that again.
Uh, robots can eat food?
Don't ask me...
Heh heh!
We have no need for food, but my astoundingly high specs include unparalleled gourmand capabilities!
I even have delicate, humanlike taste buds!
Cool! ...I think?
Well, if you don't need to eat, I'll be taking this!
Gather 'round, everyone!
Dessert is ready!
Ooh, smells good!
It tastes just like I remember!
I made custard ones, too.
Really? I'll go give one to Ryuu-chan!
This all kinda feels like a cultural festival, huh?
A cultural festival? What's that?
It's like a big open house day you have at school.
Each class has their own exhibit or food stall!
You can perform a play, put on a concert...
Or run a café or a haunted house!
Really?
I know!
Let's put on a culture festival with everyone! It'll be fun!
At school?
Yeah!
Am I...
allowed to come too?
Well, of course. Why wouldn't you be?
I don't know...
How many times do I have to tell you? That's not gonna work!
It'll be fine as long as we follow the blueprint!
Come quick!
Natsuki-sensei and Ryuu-chan are about to start hitting each other!
Unless you want to kill the electrical efficiency,
this part absolutely has to be made as light as possible.
You're talking like a brainless idiot who's never held a wrench in his life!
This axle's gonna be under constant stress.
If it breaks, efficiency'll be the least of our concerns!
I ran the calculations and it should be fine...
If everything worked like the equations say, this job would be easy!
You have no idea what you're—
No fighting!
If you don't stop right now, I'll open a piping hot can of rocket punch on you!
Calm down, okay, Natsu-kun?
You too, Ryuu-chan.
Here, it's custard, your favorite.
Huh?
Owwie! What was that for?
Nobody's fighting here.
Huh? You're not?
But you were shouting so loud, we could hear you all the way from the roof.
W-We were?
I'll admit I got a little heated.
But, you know, stuff like this was just a regular Wednesday at the Academy.
A-Anyway, I've said my piece. You need to rethink your design.
Later.
Wait.
Huh?
You don't want to help?
Honestly, I thought I'd have to do it all alone.
When I first brought it up, you didn't give off the impression that you'd be much help.
What,
you mean you thought I was stupid?
Frankly, yes. And I owe you an apology.
I thought you were stupid, and I was wrong.
I'm sorry.
What the heck?
It happened all the time when I was studying rocketry at the Academy.
All the math would work out perfectly,
but when you actually built the thing and tested it, something would always go wrong.
In times like that, practical experience was worth its weight in gold.
I mean, it's not like I have any actual experience...
But I'm sure you've picked up lots of things from helping out around the factory, right?
That's what I need more than anything right now.
Please, I'll do whatever it takes to make this thing work!
Ryuu-chan.
I wanna read more books at school!
Gimme a break... One minute you're yelling at me, next minute you're apologizing for it.
You're one weird dude, you know that?
I owe you an apology, too. I had the wrong idea about you.
Let's do this thing, bro.
Yeah.
Okay, let's pick up where we left off.
The rest of you, get lost. You'll just get in our way.
Whaaat?!
Let's go.
Ryuuji's being useful to Natsuki-san, huh?
Hm?
It's nothing.
Sorry to make you come out all this way.
Oh, it's no big deal at all.
It's not like you have anywhere else to get some girls' clothes, right?
I hope she likes them.
Eh, she's a Humanoid. Doubt she even has preferences in the first place.
You really think so?
I dunno, Atri-chan doesn't feel like a Humanoid at all.
Earlier today, she got down in the dumps
because Ryuu-chan was being useful to you, and she wasn't.
If they ever manage to make a Humanoid that's exactly the same as a real human,
should we treat it like a person? Or just a robot?
What do you think?
I...
Natsuki-san!
Coming!
What's... Hm?
Did I put this on right?
What are you wearing?
I don't know...
Wait! I've heard of this!
Why, this is the sort of provocative nightwear that shows off just the right amount,
perfect for inflaming male passions!
Natsuki-san, does this mean you want to—
Absolutely not!
What the heck were you thinking?
Huh? You asked for a change of clothes...
I was talking about pajamas!
Why'd you bring her freaking lingerie?
Huh!? You wanted pajamas?!
You can't be serious...
Say no more, Natsuki-san!
If this is how I can be of use to you, let's strike while the iron's hot!
These high specs will show you
a night
you'll never forget...
That's enough out of you!
Sorry! I'll go get some pajamas!
Huh?
Ciao!
No funny business, or the girl gets it.
What are you doing?
Don't play dumb, kiddo. I'm here to take what's mine.
Hand her over.
Don't suppose you'll still give me my fifty percent?
Can't say I will. Sorry, but it turns out I need a lot more money now.
I honestly expected you to have sold her off already, but no.
You're a real goody two-shoes, ain'tcha, kiddo?
R-Run! Atri-chan, run!
You're asking for it!
Now say it loud and clear. Say you're transferring your master privileges to me!
This is bad. If I try and rush her with this leg, she'll just sit me on my ass.
I could try to order her to fight, but Humanoids can't attack humans.
Stop trying to stall, kiddo!
Don't fucking test me!
O-Okay. I'll do it.
Natsu-kun, you can't...
Atri-
Rooocket—
Puuuuunch!
Arrrghh...
Harrumph! How'd you like that taste of my ultimate technique?
I was holding back, too, I'll have you know!
Atri...
Y-You seriously attacked a human?!
You glorified potato battery!
Hwuh!? P-P-Potato battery!?
I hope you slip and fall into an incinerator!
Stupid rust bucket! Scrap heap! Potato battery-for brains!
Harrumph! Harrumph!
Potato battery! Why, I never!
Threat successfully eliminated, Natsuki-san!
Did I do good? Was I useful?
Yeah.
Then I demand headpats!
See? I can be useful too, right?
After all, I've got the highest specs this side of the Pacific!
When I get serious, nobody can—
Atri.
Are you happy?
Yes! I've never been happier!
What's this...?
A teacher? Her?
Yeah. Her real name's Osada Hanako.
Hanako?
Ririka-chan says until a few years ago, they had a Hana-chan-sensei around here.
So she taught in this school?
Probably.
How'd she go from that to this?
I don't know,
but when she was holding the knife up to me, her hand was trembling.
I don't think she's a bad person at heart. Not really.
Well, she's got debt collectors hounding her.
She's probably backed into a corner.
Hey, you're here.
How's it going?
The resin looks good to go.
And we can probably find the other stuff we need at an abandoned hardware store or something.
Sounds like we're ready for the next phase, then.
What's that?
Getting the components we can't hope to make ourselves.
Remember this?
The motor?
Yup. And the battery to store the energy it generates.
Oh, right. Without a battery,
you can't store any electricity, no matter how much of it you generate.
Exactly. The motor will probably be easy to find.
This island's got tons of abandoned factories, after all.
The real problem is the battery.
Yeah, everybody wants them.
The school used to have some for emergencies,
but I checked earlier, and they're long gone already.
So I'm guessing...
Nothing here either!
Yeah, figures.
This one's got the battery removed, too.
Wow, you really can't find batteries anywhere, huh?
Well, the rising sea levels shut down all the power plants.
And as the global blackout went on and on,
anything even resembling a battery started selling for an absolute fortune.
So there's nothing left for us?
It's anyone's guess if we'll find anything usable,
but how about we look in the ocean?
Find anything?
Unfortunately not.
Yeah, no luck. Everything's had the batteries taken out already.
Even at the bottom of the ocean?
Guess salvage subs from the mainland got there before us.
That's a little sad, huh?
Let's see... For that amount of cash, this is the best I can offer you.
What?
That's it?
What kind of racket are you running here?
Don't like it, go shop somewhere else.
Doubt you'll find anyone that'll give you a better deal, though.
Come on, you two.
Wait!
That little lassie... Is that the same Humanoid you wanted to sell before?
Yeah. You remember that?
M-Maybe we can make a deal, then!
I'll give you this and this and this!
Uh.
I've got a buyer looking for that specific model.
They said they'll give me any price I ask for it!
For Atri?
In other words, someone finally recognizes my exceptional value?
Uh, yeah, sure.
These high specs don't come cheap, after all!
Now, go ahead and repeat after me,
"Atri, you're worth more than any toaster in the world!"
If that's not enough for you, I'll throw in this, too!
Whaddaya say, kid?
Why's this specific model of Humanoid worth so much more?
Mmm, because it's rare, I guess?
Huh?
There's no way that rarity is enough to explain a price tag like this.
There has to be a better reason.
I dunno what to tell ya...
You have any documentation or something?
The fourth generation Yamasaki Factory model...
All it says is "discontinued."
You said they got recalled, right?
Why was that? Because they looked too human?
That's the official line, anyway.
But who knows the real reason?
Manufacturers always keep that stuff under wraps.
You'd be surprised how many Humanoid collectors there are.
They'll shell out the dough for anything rare.
That's just how it goes.
Collectors might be one thing,
but then why did Grandma leave her so well preserved?
Just because she's rare?
It's definitely more than just her physical appearance...
She must've been built to have human-like thoughts and emotions as well.
What are we gonna do now?
Huh?
Ryuu-chan's finally motivated, but we've run into a wall.
Oh, that.
Worst-case scenario, I'll just grab the battery from the sub and use that.
Huh? But then you wouldn't be able to dive anymore.
Well, them's the breaks.
I'm not sure I like that...
Wait.
Hm?
You should just sell me.
Atri-chan...
You can get all the batteries you need if you sell me, right?
Enough to light up the whole school, right?
And I'll finally be useful to you, right?
Weren't you gonna be my leg?
You said you didn't need me for that.
And what about Grandma's order?
I told you before.
Humanoids are born to fulfill their masters' desires.
And you're okay with this?
You'd never see me again.
No, I'm not.
I'd miss you.
But if it would make you happy...
Atri-chan...
This discussion's over. I'm not selling you.
Then how about using my battery?
I'm sure the battery inside me must be pretty high-spec.
After all, I'm—
Never!
Natsuki-san...
Fuck...