Mmm... I told you, I'm low-voltage...
What, you wanna sleep till the cows come home?
Geez.
Here. Brush your teeth.
Ever consider doing it yourself for once?
You can get 'em cleaner than I can.
Aren't you high-spec?
Better hurry, or we'll be late for school.
Ho ha' ou mae a hehihion?
Wait till I'm done.
Yeah.
I have.
Healhy?
Okay, that's it!
Go get changed right this instant!
Wow, that's a big yawn.
Didn't get enough sleep?
Natsuki hasn't been letting me do much of that lately...
Really?!
Don't say it like that. You'll put ideas in their heads.
Oh, hey. Natsuki-sensei.
What are you doing in our classroom?
What about your class?
Okay, class!
Before we get started today, Natsuki-sensei has an important announcement to make.
So, uh, this is kinda coming out of left field,
but I'm gonna be going to the mainland.
Huh?
I'll be going back to the Academy.
Uh, Sensei...
Are you quitting school?
Are you abandoning us?
No, no.
I've just decided I want to go back to school and do some studying myself.
Ririka inspired me.
Huh?
Even in a world without light, you were serious about reading books.
You studied hard, and you worked hard to achieve your goals.
Seeing that made me realize...
I needed to make a change in myself.
Sensei...
What are you gonna study at the Academy?
Back in the day, I wanted to get on a rocket and go to space.
I wanted to get the world moving again.
But now I want to study about Humanoids.
Stuff like how humans and Humanoids can forge a good relationship,
or what we need to do to be happy together.
I want to find the answers to big questions like that.
Thank you.
You can do it!
Sensei.
What about Atri?
I told her she could decide, and she said she'd come with me.
Right?
Atri?
Uh, yes?
What, were you sleeping sitting up?
Er, uh...
Sensei! It's gonna be a while before you leave, right?
Yeah!
You better say something before you disappear on us!
Looks like you've got one heck of a goodbye party to look forward to, huh?
I hope you're ready.
Huh? You don't need to-
Yes we do.
This kind of thing is for all of us, not just you.
Yeah.
We want to give you a good send-off.
Okay.
Ooh! Someone's gotten pretty understanding, huh?
Oh, shut up.
Welp, if there's anything I can help with, gimme a holler.
Says he'll come running 'cause he's got nothing better to do.
Y-Yeah.
Ryuuji.
[MISSING]
Er...
You don't have to do this if you don't want to...
Come on, what is it?
Once I'm gone, can you carry on the salvaging business?
You can have the boat and sub.
I don't need those junkers.
Oh...
I'll just borrow 'em from you.
And I'll do the salvaging.
Ryuuji...
I mean, hey, when we pluck people's keepsakes and stuff out of the ocean,
it makes 'em happy, right?
I've been thinking it ain't a bad line of work.
Me and Minamo'll help, too!
Yeah!
That's great!
I'm kinda surprised how pure a guy Natsuki is.
I'm not.
Atri, what're you doing?
Nothing! I'm coming!
There. That should do it.
Look how late it is.
We haven't even had dinner yet.
You know what, you're right.
Ryuuji is going to be borrowing the boat, right?
We didn't have to clean it out this much, did we?
Nah, I wanna give it to him as a nice, clean slate.
Makes it easier to work.
Eh, this'll do for dinner...
Ohhh no, it won't!
And why not?
Me and my high specs can hardly allow you to consume a meal as paltry as that!
I'll make dinner!
At this hour? You sure?
You have nothing to fear!
Under Minamo's tutelage, my cooking is improving by leaps and bounds!
With my skills, give me thirty minutes and-
I made a mistaaaaake!
Good ol' vindictive microwave.
That's a violation of the Robot Discrimination Act!
Say your prayers and taste my rocket punch!
Yeah, you're right. Sorry for being racist.
Huh?
I'm glad...
you didn't go anywhere.
I'm gonna go check on the sub.
You've been a real trooper, huh?
It says, "Thank you."
You can tell?
Yes. Just a vague sense.
Well, coming from a Humanoid, it's gotta be true.
Right back at you.
I'm counting on you, partner.
Um, Natsuki...
Hm? What's up?
There's something I'd like to talk about...
This thing!?
Catherine said if we're going to the mainland together,
we ought to make things clear.
What?
Um,
she said I shouldn't be an easy woman...
God dammit, Catherine...
And wait, do you even know what "easy woman" means?
Yes. I did some searching.
What.
In short...
W-
Wait!
Natsuki...
Wait! Slow down!
I feel like, you know...
we should take this a little slow...
You know, take some time to get to know each other's feelings...
I know.
Huh?
I didn't understand any of this before, but now I do.
It's a very important thing, and it takes a lot of courage.
My heart is bursting out of my chest.
Atri...
Natsuki, um...
Do you...
love me?
I-
I?
I,
uh...
You what?
Atri, I-
Aaah, no, I changed my mind!
Don't say it!
I said don't say it! It's too embarrassing!
Hm?
Hwuh?
I swear...
Sorry.
No, it's not your fault. It's Catherine's.
No, I came to her about this.
I told her I was feeling restless right around here,
and I could hardly live with myself,
and I didn't know what to do...
Atri.
Why don't we go take a walk?
Pretty...
Yeah.
Atri.
Yes?
I don't see you as a human girl.
Yes...
But I don't see you as just a Humanoid, either.
To me, you're a very precious, unique thing all to yourself.
Natsuki...
I don't know how a Humanoid with a heart and a human like me
should go about building a relationship.
Do we just go for a normal romantic relationship,
or should it be something different?
I want us to find the answer together.
For us, and for humans and Humanoids to come.
So...
I'm counting on you.
Yes!
Atri?
Atri...
Hey. Atri. Atri!
What's wrong? Atri!
Up until then,
she was operating without any perception or motor issues.
Judging by the symptoms, the problem's probably with...
Where is it? It's gotta be here...
Found it!
Come on, come on...
So it is the battery. Let's see, charging methods...
"Due to the high power draw,
household charging presents significant hazards.
To prevent battery death,
it is recommended to conduct periodic maintenance at the retailer..."
Shit!
She's low on battery?
So you can't charge her on your own?
What happened to the manufacturer?
Even if the company goes under, there's still maintenance places, right?
On the mainland, yes. But...
There's a recall out on her model.
They'll just take her away.
Oh...
What do we do?
If things keep up, she'll lose her memory.
And then...
Natsuki, how could you?!
Atri...
How could you come to school without me?
You...
You can move?
Of course I can!
I have to take care of my dear Shiina-sama-
Huh? What did I just...
Natsuki...
Natsuki, where are you?
Atri...
I can't see.
Is it nighttime now?
Natsuki... I feel cold...
Get some sleep.
Huh?
That's an order. Don't say a word.
Just sleep.
Atri...
Yeah, we're canceling class today.
I'll hit up my network from my detective days.
The rest of you, go look for any information that might be useful. Okay?
Nothing decent, huh?
Nope...
I mean, hey, she was manufactured decades ago...
Is she gonna be okay?
I think she's in some kind of sleep mode to preserve her memory.
How long will she last?
I don't know.
I'm sure she'll be fine.
She was at the bottom of the ocean for years, right?
And her battery didn't run out then.
Years...
Am I wrong?
No...
Atri's logbook...
"Nonko told me to sleep here.
She said that this would be my cradle."
What does that mean?
Cradle?
The capsule.
Huh?
It's the capsule!
When Atri was sleeping, the capsule was providing her with power!
Of course!
So where's the capsule now?
It's probably still...
Come on...
How's it looking, Natsu?
Good. I'm almost there.
Atri...
I can't let Atri forget about what we have...
Or it'll be like it never happened at all!
This place is looking pretty bad...
Must be because of that storm.
Natsu. Natsu!
Everything's okay. I found the capsule.
But...
But what?
Nothing. I'll give it a shot!
Look, I'm sorry for working you so hard you got this beat-up.
But...
I need your help!
Almost there!
Yes!
Natsu?
We're all good. Lower the hook!
It's in great condition...
And it's completely waterproofed.
She must've known it'd end up in the ocean.
Natsu.
It's not reacting.
Is there a button you push, or something?
No...
Maybe it needs electricity?
No, I know my grandma.
She'd never rely on external assistance.
She'd handle everything herself.
Atri...
Whoa, what the heck?
It sensed Atri, and now it's charging her.
She'll be okay.
Really?
Yeah.
Can you see us?
Atri...
Good morning.
Natsuki...
You'd better thank my grandma.
Eden...
This capsule told me...
about Nonko's final order.