Was it all a lie?
What's the matter?
Ah!
Did you have a bad dream ag-
Shut up!
Were you just pretending to have a heart?
Pretending? What does "pretending-"
It means lying!
It means saying things you don't mean!
I don't know.
My job is to be useful to you and make you happy.
That's the motivation behind everything I do.
When you said you might have a heart, did you mean it?
Did you say that because you really do think you have a heart?
No.
Then here's an order for you!
Stop pretending you have a heart!
Stop trying to make me happy!
Yes.
Why did you lie to me?
I have already answered that question.
Do you love me?
As you are now,
I hate you.
Don't follow me!
I'm high-spec!
Was it all a lie?
That time, and that time,
and that time, and that time, and that time, all of it...
Was it all a lie?
You sure he's okay? Whatever happened, it was serious.
Yeah... When we found him sprawled out on the road,
I thought I was gonna have a heart attack.
Thanks, you two. I'll ask him what happened.
You sure?
Yeah.
Okay, you can take it from here.
Did you two fight?
Minamo...
Did you know?
Know what?
No, I knew all along. She's a Humanoid.
There's no way she could have a heart.
She was just scouring her massive stores of data,
cross-referencing situations and reactions,
and picking the optimal solution.
She laughed when she was supposed to,
got angry when she was supposed to,
faithfully running her programs
to manufacture her facial expressions and tailor her words.
That's what Humanoids are.
You know what I think?
I think that's no different from what we humans do.
I know I'm like that.
I look at the other person, think about what I should say to them,
and choose my words based on how they look and act.
I don't know what a heart is.
Even if you know it's wrong, even if you have nothing to gain,
you'll still say or do something stupid.
I think you're right, and she really does have a heart.
But I think she's doubting herself.
She's nervous about having a heart.
Hot...
Sorry. I figured you were cold.
Should I have let it cool a bit?
It's fine.
This is just right.
Morning!
I went to check on Atri-chan, and she was doing fine.
She said she'd go to school.
Oh.
I'll tell everyone you're out with a cold, okay?
No, I'll go.
Hm?
My students need someone to teach them.
But...
Besides,
I can't exactly avoid Atri forever.
I had a feeling you'd say that. I brought your uniform!
Sure won't stop raining, huh?
Yeah...
Oh!
Natsuki-sensei!
Huh?
Where's Atrin?
Is she not here?
She said she'd come...
What's this?
No return address.
It's a report on the recall of Yamasaki Factory's fourth-generation models.
Yamasaki Factory...
So it's about Atri!
Yeah. This probably came from someone who knows she's here.
Rampage?
"In defiance of its user's orders, the unit in question infiltrated a school
and severely injured its students."
Atri did that?
I don't know if she really was "the unit in question."
But they only ever sold a grand total of 58 of her model.
Once they recalled them all,
just one, "the unit in question," broke out and went missing.
But Yamasaki Factory covered that up.
Meanwhile, the hubbub surrounding the recall
soured demand for Humanoids, and the company went under.
And so they never recovered the missing unit.
And that unit was Atri?
There's no proof.
This report could be completely made up.
But I'm responsible for these kids' safety, so I have to err on the side of caution.
So I told her, "I'm sorry, but I can't let you in here."
You should get going. I'll handle things here.
I owe you one, after all.
Thanks.
Atri turned violent?
Is that why her memory was erased?
Or maybe she's just pretending,
and she really...
Who are you?
My name is Yasuda.
I was head of Yamasaki Factory's research and development department.
For Humanoids.
I apologize for disturbing your plans,
but could I invite you for a little chat?
This rain just won't let up, will it?
You must have it rough with that leg.
Believe me, I understand. I'm the same way.
Skip the small talk. Just get to the point.
Was Atri the one who got violent at that school?
I trust you recognize that string.
Atri's log...
YHN-04B-009.
That is that unit's official serial number.
The fourth generation was made to keep written logs
in an effort to pursue more human methods
of building memories and learning.
"Today, I met my first master.
Her name is-"
Shiina...
A penny for your thoughts.
No... This can't be real!
To create a copy of ourselves.
Is that the culmination of human scientific progress,
or is it an inviolable taboo?
That was the question Professor Konishi sought to answer.
Konishi...
My mentor. The one who created the Humanoids.
The rampage at the school
ended Professor Konishi's career--and eventually, life.
It is my duty to recover that incomplete model
and dispose of it.
I consider it the bare minimum goodwill I can show the world and the Professor.
Can I trust you to cooperate?
There is only one unit left.
Once I dispose of that unit, my work will be complete.
I understand how you must feel.
The fourth generation was impeccably made.
They comprehend human emotion algorithms
well enough to uphold the illusion that they possess genuine emotions themselves.
But they do not actually have hearts.
Surely you have realized this.
Your feelings, no matter how strong, will never reach it.
I assure you that the only heart to break
will be your own.
I... need some time to think.
I'm home.
Welcome home.
You're acting different today.
I am following your orders.
If I told you to act like you always do, would you?
I will follow orders.
It's an order, then.
Act like you always do.
Welcome home, Nat suki-san!
Are you hungry?
Yeah. Come to think of it, I haven't had anything to eat.
Oh, we can't have that!
Wait right there! I'll heat up Mom's Cooking, Part Two!
Curry, right?
H-How'd you know?
Curry is a classic day-after-nikujaga meal.
They use the same ingredients.
Really? Your deductive prowess astounds me!
Atri.
Yes?
Stop pretending you have a heart.
Yes.
Dinner is served.
Does it taste good?
If I said yes, would it make you happy?
Yes.
Liar!
You wouldn't be happy!
You'd just make a log in your AI saying you made the right choice!
Correct.
I am a Humanoid.
I apologize.
No...
I'm the one who should apologize.
Of course you wouldn't know how to react to my nonsense.
Yes.
Are you going out?
I want to be alone. Don't follow me.
What's the plan?
The low-pressure system's wind speeds are still increasing,
so people will need to be very careful out in the rain.
We can expect heavy winds around coastal areas, so ships...
What was that?
I'm out at sea!
This is bad...
What the...?
Atri!
Ririka came and said that the school is in danger, so I have gone with her.
The notebook...
Shit!
Yeah. Yeah, that's how it is, isn't it?
Why didn't I understand
something so...
Atri...
Atri!
Hana-chan-sensei...
How could you take some little kids hostage?
By all means, relax.
They will be free to go just as soon as that unit arrives.
Don't be afraid. It won't be much longer.
Ririka went to go get Atri-chan, right?
Yeah. They should be here any minute now.
And here it comes.
Where is your master?
Where's Natsu?
That's the thing! I couldn't find him!
Natsu-kun...
Well, no matter.
Come over here.
Hana-chan-sensei!
There, there. It's okay. Everything's okay now.
What are you going to do with Atri-chan?
Atri-chan!
Oh, the show's just getting started.
Burn the sight into your eyes.
Witness just how dangerous this Humanoid is.
Atri-chan!
You mother-
Shut up and watch.
Honestly...
You attack a school, disgrace the Professor,
and even escape on top of that.
How much suffering must you cause before you're satisfied?
Were you that determined to see your own creator,
see the Professor's life fall apart?
Atri-chan!
Fuck...
Come on...
Come on!
I need to go...
Need to go be with...
I need to go be with that bootleg LLM!
She's cheeky, for a robot...
She keeps bragging about her high specs right before screwing up...
She's annoying, and she's too meddlesome for her own good...
She's got a heart more beautiful than any human's...
And she's my piece-of-crap Humanoid!
You defective wretch.
If it weren't for you, the Professor...
The Professor! The Professor!
The Professor!
If it weren't for you and what you did...
Atri!
Stop it.
You've had your fun.
What? Surely you jest!
This is a Humanoid. This is nothing to it.
Isn't that right?
Stop it!
If there's one thing you're good at, it's inspiring empathy in humans.
Really, you terrify me!
You hopeless,
damnable monster!
Atri!
Natsuki-san...