Someone...
Anyone...
Help me...
Atri?
I'll be your leg.
My leg?
Yes.
I'll make your wish come true.
No. Stop it.
Atri!
What is it?
Natsuki-san, you silly old bear...
As a Humanoid, serving her master is her top priority.
But...
Of course not.
I'd miss you.
But if it would make you happy...
But...
it's pretty.
Atri's more than just a Humanoid...
Huh?
What?
Phew...
Awfully hot tea you got here.
You're lucky Natsuki-san even let you in here in the first place.
I hope you appreciate that.
So what happened? Someone attack you?
Nah.
Natsuki-san! My sensors are detecting alcohol!
Oh, come on. You fell into the ocean in a drunken stupor?
Oh, shut up! Ain't nobody can handle life without a little booze!
I tell ya hwat, there's only two types of people in the world!
People what drink, and people what don't drink!
And people what're none of the above!
That's three...
I see logic isn't on the menu tonight.
Shaddap! Don't you be smart with me!
Times like this, you just go, "Oh, okay, you're so smart," capisce!?
Oh, okay, you're so smart.
Put a little enthusiasm into it, why don't you!?
You don't know a damn thing!
Atri, you deal with her.
Dun wanna.
Oh, nobody even cares about me anyway...
Lord knows you're never selling the robot.
Well, yeah.
Then I just get to sit here waiting to die.
It's really that bad?
Work as a private eye long enough, and you start brushing up against the seedy underbelly of society.
I've got no money. You can guess the rest, right?
Even though you used to be a teacher?
How do you know that?
A very stupid private eye told me.
What? I was wondering where that went! You rotten thief!
Hey, don't be mean! You're lucky I didn't loot it and chuck it into the ocean!
You should be thank-
Natsuki-san!
Is that the debt collectors?
How should I know!?
I didn't think they were this viol-
This isn't good.
I'll be a decoy.
You take that chance to run for it.
Atri, you go with Catherine.
Huh?
No! I can't afford to leave your-
That's an order.
You can't move to your full potential if you're stuck with me.
Go with Catherine and take out our enemies!
Natsuki-san...
Yes sir!
Welp, let's go pick up the goods.
All we're after is the Humanoid.
Push comes to shove...
You listening? Step one, we go to that storage container over there.
Shit! There it is! After it!
Get back here!
It's naptime for you!
Where'd it go?
Hop on!
They're after you! We have to get out of here!
No!
Huh?
Natsuki-san told me to take out our enemies!
Shit! We lost 'em!
All we can do now is see if we can loot the place for parts and-
I hope you know what you're doing!
I do!
What now!?
You ain't going nowhere!
Rocket...
Ow... Huh?
What was that?
Atri! You okay?
Uh, yes.
Wait, you're the guy from the-
It wasn't my idea, I swear!
They said they'd reward me handsomely if I brought them the Humanoid!
That doesn't change the fact that you attacked us.
The police may not be what they used to be, but with this much evidence,
I'll be impressed if they don't show you the inside of a cell!
Wait! We can talk this out!
Okay.
I'm always down for some quid pro quo.
Hasta la vista!
And don't come back, you got that?
Sure wasn't expecting that to be how I paid back my debt.
The world works in strange ways, huh?
Are you sure you didn't want to ask for money, Natsuki-san?
He said he'd pay any price.
Nothing good comes of getting too greedy.
Besides,
the compensation I got was more than good enough.
Welp, I'd better be going. Sorry, and thanks.
Going where?
Who knows? I lost my bike, so not far.
I'll think about it on the road.
Oh, and this is for you.
A little something to make up for everything.
Keep it. You need the money, don't you?
Not any more than you do, right?
Shut up and let me save face.
See ya.
Wait.
Don't you want to come back here?
Huh? You know I can't do that!
I abandoned this place. I don't have a home anymore.
There's the school, isn't there?
Listen to yourself.
I saw the place.
Half the building's underwater.
And all the teachers are gone, I'm sure.
But the school's still there.
What do you mean?
It's almost time for class.
Why don't you go see for yourself?
Class?
Yeah. They're still having 'em.
Got students here in need of an education, after all.
The teacher isn't exactly qualified, though.
School...
Okay, Ririka-chan! Start reading from where we left off yesterday.
Mmkay.
"Gon! So you were the one giving me chestnuts!"
Gon nodded, his eyes still closed.
Hyouju...
Hana-chan-sensei?
It's Hana-chan-sensei!
What are you doing here?
It's you guys...
Hana-chan-sensei!
S-Stop calling me that!
My name's Catherine now.
Catherine?
Doesn't stick the landing, huh?
Qu-Quiet, you! Catherine's a way cooler name!
Really? I really gotta question your taste.
I'm sorry, but I did some digging into your past.
I heard you were an incredible teacher, and everybody here loved you.
Well, your info's dead wrong.
I abandoned this place. I still had students, but I took off and ran.
I couldn't take it anymore.
But you came back.
I love this city too much to give up on it.
I want to make it every bit as lively and bustling as it used to be.
We don't have much at the moment...
But Hana-chan-sensei,
will you please be everyone's teacher again?
Come back to us.
Hana-chan-sensei!
Sensei!
Stay away from me! Stay away...
Sensei? Are you okay?
Don't cry!
You're catching the feels too, huh?
Oh, shut up!
We're gonna make that generator or die trying, got it!?
We're gonna light the school up and make it just like it used to be!
Yeah.
And if we wanna do that, first, we need batteries.
We have to scrounge 'em up somewhere.
Oh, I got us some.
What?
And I couldn't've done it without Hana-chan-sensei and Atri.
You mean...!
Yeah. We're gonna restore this school to its former glory.
Good grief, that's hard.
This is gonna be harder than I thought.
This'll take me a month, easy.
If only I had an electric drill...
Atri.
Yes? What is it?
Can you give it a try?
I just need to make a hole right here, right?
Yeah. Go for it.
You think she's got this?
Sure, she's a Humanoid, but those spindly little arms-
Holy shit!
All in a day's work for a combat robot!
Huh? You're a combat robot?
Source: her ass.
[smug robot noises]
Natsuki-sensei!
Well, give us more where that came from!
You got it!
Ooh, you're done?
When we carved the styrofoam, it exploded and started snowing!
Wow, that came out pretty good.
Yeah! Hana-chan-sensei helped with the finishing touches!
Slow down!
Did she, now?
Thanks.
Wh-Whatever.
I just didn't want the kids to do it unsupervised...
Anyway, are you sure this is gonna work?
Everything checks out in theory.
First, we bust a hole in the floor
and cover the walls so water doesn't get into this room from outside.
What happens at high tide, then?
Seawater comes in through the hole.
And of course, it leaves the same way at low tide.
Use that power to spin a turbine, and you've got a tidal power generator.
The mechanism's really simple when you get down to it, so I think we have a shot.
But I've heard waves can be pretty strong, can't they?
Sure they won't break anything?
The amount of seawater and the pressure it puts on the turbine aren't gonna be constant.
And the salt in the seawater opens up the possibility of corrosion.
That's what makes tidal power generation tricky.
Long-term stability and replicability are paramount.
Stability?
What's that?
It means it needs to be sturdy as a rock.
And easy to rebuild when it breaks.
In this classroom, we're gonna put resin and reinforced fibers together
to make FRP for our turbine.
FRP resists corrosion, and it's plenty strong for our purposes.
And if it breaks, all you need is the model,
and you can make a replacement in no time flat.
So that's what...
Yeah. Sorry I gave you the annoying job.
But thanks to you, I think we're gonna have a great turbine.
Food's ready!
But first, we'd better fill our bellies.
Atri.
Let me know when you're done digging the hole.
I'll be grabbing dinner upstairs.
Huh? You're going without me?
Yeah! Even an underling should get to eat with the rest of the gang.
I'm not an underling, but I agree with the rest of that!
Yeah, but you don't even need to eat, right?
Well, right now, I'm your leg, so I have to stay with you!
Relax. I'll be surrounded by friends.
But...
I still want to go with you.
When we got attacked,
and you ordered me to go with Catherine, I didn't like that, either.
I was worried sick that you'd get hurt while I was gone.
What's the harm? We're gonna have to wait for the resin to harden anyway.
All right. Come with us.
Yes! I'd love to!
So she feels unease and loneliness?
That basically means she's got all the same emotions a human does.
And if that's why her generation was deemed too dangerous and recalled, then Atri...
is less a Humanoid, and more...
Rub-a-dub-dub, thanks for the itadakimasu!
Yummy!
It's been a while since I've had rice from a mess kit, but this ain't half bad!
Great! Tooru-kun worked extra hard on it.
Yeah!
And we've got miso soup, too!
Yippee! Look at all the ingredients!
Today's our lucky day!
And here's some for you, Atri.
Huh?
Are you sure?
Hey, everyone else is eating.
You don't wanna feel left out, right?
How is it?
I love it.
Welp, time to take another whack at this thing!
Yeah!
There's more where that came from!
Ugh, you really gotta learn to do this yourself.
I'm tired enough from working all day as it is.
Bu' hearly whi's'll hesh a higher hrishe...
Would you stop talking with your mouth open?
Nice and clean!
Now this is beauty befitting my staggeringly high specs!
I know!
What?
Will you wash my back, too?
I can't reach it very well my-
No.
Awww! Why not!?
Because I said so!
You're such a meanie, Natsuki-san!
So she has no sense of shame, huh?
Guess she's not entirely human...
Natsuki-san! I'm turning off the lights!
Whatever. I can think about this stuff tomorrow.
Wait, why are you wearing that again!?
Oh, but Ryuuji said this is what men like.
I'm gonna deck him...
And this makes it easier for you catch some lucky glimpses,
just like last time!
You noticed?
Of course I noticed! My specs are out of this-
Whatever! Just forget it!
No way! I even recorded it in my logs!
Besides, it makes me happy.
It makes me feel like you need me.
N-Now you're just making stuff up.
Freaking Roomba.
So you compound your offenses, do you?
Cease your racism at once!
I told you you had a rocket punch in your future if you kept it up!
Natsuki-san?
Sweet dreams.
I checked the wiring. It's all good.
Great. Atri, you make sure it spins.
Okay!
It's working!
Does that mean we're making electricity?
Yeah.
Okay.
Now we just wait for nighttime.
Look!
It's spinning! It's spinning!
Wow... It's getting faster and faster!
Is this gonna turn on the lights?
Yeah. Minamo, can you turn the knob?
I think you should do the honors.
Huh?
Come on, turn the knob!
We did it!
Ryuuji!
Y-Yeah!
All right!
When I came to this town, I wasn't expecting anything.
I didn't want to come crawling back to my grandmother,
and I thought I had no future to look forward to now that I'd dropped out.
Can I go get a book to read?
I wanna go see the fan!
Don't trip and fall!
I can't believe you really pulled it off.
Natsu-kun...
Thank you... Thank you for coming back...
Oh, don't cry... You're such a baby.
But I'm just so...
Same to you, Atri. Thank you.
Can I take this to mean that everyone's happy?
You sure can. What about you? Are you happy?
Yes, I am.
But I can't cry.
I don't have the functionality.
But the robot I met there,
the robot who'd been slumbering on the ocean floor for years,
shone a light into my life.
And that robot...
Then you can smile instead.
Smile?
Like this!
Yeah!