Um, Sensei?
Yeah?
I have a question...
Oh, this formula?
You've got the right approach. You just-
Natsuki-san!
I've thought about it, and I need to stay by your side!
You need my support!
We've been over this. I'm perfectly safe when I'm teaching a class.
Now go back to your classroom.
You shouldn't be sneaking out of class.
But...
Atri-chan?
How many times do I have to teach you this lesson?
The elementary schoolers are in the next room over!
Y-Yes, ma'am...
I have to say, I never expected Natsu-kun to volunteer to be a teacher.
And for high schoolers, at that. He's barely any older than us.
He sure is smart!
He went to the Academy, remember?
And it's making him the talk of the town, FYI.
Huh?
Literally.  The town's abuzz.
People can't shut up about the hot young man who's just started teaching here.
I present to you Exhibit A.
Can you, like, get off your high horse? Nobody cares that you've been here longer.
Am I wrong?
Yes, you're wrong!
I only came here 'cause I heard the electricity was back, and I wanted to check it out!
Come here to learn next time.
Whatever, jerk.
But yeah, that's my story. My name's Youko.
Oh, yeah. Nice to meet you.
I heard you were working all by yourself to get the school back up and running!
You have any problems, you come to me. I'll be a lot more useful than this nerd.
Just to set the record straight, it was me and Natsu who built that generator, got it?
Oh, please.
We all know you were just Natsuki-sensei's assistant.
You wish!
Oh, I'm wrong, am I?
What, you think I'm stupid, too?
Stupid?
Just a little farther...
For the millionth time, don't talk underwater.
A cable...
Must be a TV or internet cable or something from a while ago.
Let's move on.
One more block, and you should see a house with a chimney.
Gotcha.
I never would've thought of running a salvaging service.
Lots of people out there want us to find their sunken houses
and dig up stuff with sentimental value.
But here's a better question. Isn't now your chance?
For what?
Natsu!
Hwuh!?
You seriously thought I wouldn't notice?
Twiddle your thumbs any longer, and someone's gonna steal him!
Youko says even more girls are gonna start showing up next week.
More students at school is a good thing.
Hana-chan-sensei is even teaching the younger kids for us.
That's not my point, and you know it!
Huh?
Don't you want to be with Natsu?
Long-term?
Yeah, that's gotta be it.
I told you, I can't-
You're right. Tasty things make you happy, huh?
Oh, you found it!
Thank you kindly.
It isn't much, but here's a token of my appreciation.
Bartering?
Yeah, uh, see, we have certain prices for our services...
Thank you. We'll take them.
Atri, can you carry these?
Aye-aye!
I swear...
Dude's too nice for his own good.
Something's fishy.
Huh? What do you mean?
Natsuki-san was smiling.
Just now, and when we were underwater, too.
And that's fishy?
Of course!
A little while ago, nothing could get him to smile.
Hey, a lot's changed. He's a teacher now,
he's got girls making googly eyes at him...
Anyone would get a little giddy.
It's like he's got his own personal harem.
Harem...
Searching, searching...
Atri-chan, wai-
N-N-N-Natsuki-san, you horndog!
It's rocket punch time!
Hwuh!?
Wait!
It's not like that! It's just not!
Really?
Ryuu-chan!
Hey, you don't know. Maybe it is like that.
Huh?
When guys are on cloud nine like this, that's your best chance at knocking 'em down.
Knock them down?
Any other day, Natsu doesn't care about that stuff at all, right?
You're looking at the chance of a lifetime.
To what, punish him by knocking him down into the sea?
That seems a bit much for him.
He can't swim, after all.
Atri.
Why don't you and me take those watermelons to Ririka and the kids?
No.
Now look...
I can't afford to leave Natsuki-san's side.
Hey, Natsu!
Can Atri and I take these watermelons to the kids?
Sure! Go with Ryuuji, Atri!
Huh? But-
Master's orders!
Hup...
Come on, let's go.
If I must... Well, I quite like the kids, so it's all right with me...
I'm gonna need to replace some of the hatch parts soon, or I'm in trouble...
Natsu-kun, want me to get dinner ready while Atri's out?
You'd do that? Thanks.
Just let her do it herself sometime, okay?
I'm teaching her everything I know.
Who, Atri?
Yeah. She really wants your approval.
Just the other day, I taught her how to make nikujaga.
Atri can make nikujaga...
Hey.
What do you think of Atri?
Well, hmm...
She's a nice girl. She's cute...
No, uh, that's not what I mean.
Remember what you were saying?
How she doesn't feel like a robot at all?
Oh, yeah.
I mean, her smile looks real to me.
Her happiness looks like it really comes from the heart!
Maybe she really does have one--a heart.
The first-ever Humanoid to come with an AI capable of human-like emotion...
You think that's what she is?
I don't know.
Not like I have any way to prove it.
But if that's what she is, it'd explain everything.
Why Grandma preserved her so carefully in that capsule,
why her manufacturer tried to recall her...
Remember when we turned on the lights in the school?
When I saw her smile back then, it made me think.
If she really is happy, and she really is smiling from the heart,
then I have to treat her like a human.
Natsu-kun...
All right, snack time!
Eat it while it's still cold, got it?
Yeah!
It's so sweet!
Don't just stand there. Go get some for yourself!
Tres bien!
I love Minamo so much. This is great!
For someone who doesn't need food, you sure can put away a lot of it.
I'm capable of perceiving taste and prioritizing consumption of food with the optimal flavor.
Once again, proof positive of my sky-high specs!
Here's hoping that functionality comes in handy for your own cooking.
Natsuki-san has hopes for me...
You can count on me!
It was a figure of speech.
Hwuh!?
He's not?
Yeah. Natsu-kun being happy lately
doesn't have anything to do with girls.
Then what is it?
Apparently Atri-chan caused it all.
Atri?
Wait, is that guy into-
You're kidding me. She's a Humanoid!
She's a robot!
No!
It's not about romance or anything!
Then what is it about?
Mmm, how do I put this...
I don't think Natsu-kun's interested in that stuff right now.
What're you writing?
Don't look!
What, your logs?
I figure your master would have the right to see those.
I'm of the understanding that a girl's diary is supposed to be private!
Well, whatever.
"When I told him he couldn't look, Natsuki-san got pouty."
Huh? Don't write anything weird!
Oh, it's not weird at all. I'm just recording events as they happened.
What are you doing!?
Putting my logbook away. It's very important.
Just lower your hem already!
Why so bashful?
It's nothing you don't see when we go to sleep.
It comes off different depending on how you show it, okay!?
Fascinating.
I swear. Maybe she really doesn't have emotions after all?
No, even humans have to acquire a sense of shame as they grow up.
She could just be immat-
What are you doing?
Nothing. Just noting how cute you look when you blush bright red.
Quit clowning around and get your butt in the bath!
Robot harassment! Robot harassment!
You think so?
Yeah. Minamo says he's not interested in romance, but what's your read?
Uh, hmm...
I dunno. I haven't talked to him that much.
But if anyone knows...
That kiddo's love life!?
Yeah. You're an adult--what do you think?
Well, he's got plenty of book smarts, but he looks like a total late bloomer in romance...
So Minamo's right, and he's not interested?
I wouldn't be so sure.
Huh?
Nine times out of ten, it means he's already got his heart set on someone!
What?
He went to the Academy, didn't he?
Maybe he met his soulmate there.
That's what I'm reading from how calm he is, anyway.
I oughta ask him straight.
What, you?
Oh, please! He'll never spill the beans to the likes of you!
And why not!?
She's right. It's easier to talk about this stuff with the opposite sex.
So, what's the plan?
Oh, well. It's not right for a teacher to butt into her students' love lives,
but hey, he's a teacher, not a student.
You'll help?
But how?
Easy as pie.
Gimme your ear...
What? Me!?
Now, you've gotta make him think you're dead serious, got it?
I want you to have the delivery perfect by next Sunday!
Nooooo!
Someone, please, kill me...
Yeah, uh, guess I'm on the sidelines for this one.
This isn't Taa-kun!
Aw, I'm sorry! We'll have him looking good as new in no time, okay?
It's in a state of considerable deterioration.
I would imagine this plushie is fit for disposal.
Don't say that!
We're so sorry!
It ain't easy being a salvager, huh?
There's no guarantee anything's gonna come out looking as good as it did going in.
Think we should hike the prices?
Considering the workload, our current rates are gonna put us in the red.
No, it's fine.
As long as it makes someone on the island happy,
it's a job worth doing.
But on the other hand, fuel doesn't exactly grow on trees...
Sensei!
You're Natsuki-sensei, right?
Who're you?
Youko! I'm in your class!
Oh, the one who showed up a little while ago.
Yeah... See, there's something I wanted to talk to you about...
I hope I'm not bothering you, or anything...
The formula from the other day?
You start by factoring the-
No!
Sensei, I... I love you!
Sensei! Do you already have someone else?
Is it Minamo-chan? It is, isn't it?
Minamo?
It's not her?
Oh, then is it that glasses girl?
Where'd that even come from?
Then is it...
Atri-chan?
Huh?
Come on, you've gotta be kidding me! Atri's a Humanoid. And just look at her!
But I've heard you cuddle her in your sleep...
She told you about that!?
Wait, so it's true!?
N-No, wait!
O-Of course I'm not into-
Oh my god.
Then who is it!?
Word of advice from someone who's been teaching longer than you have.
You gotta do this shit right.
A lady from his childhood?
That's who Natsu-kun likes?
That's what he said.
Can't forget her.
Holy crap, the dork's too pure for this world!
Still, she was his first love?
I think he said it happened when he was nine...
What with the accident and all,
he was going through a lot mentally...
And there was a lady who saved his life at the time.
I never knew...
He said she was about five years older than him.
What's her name? Where is she now?
That's the thing. He doesn't know a thing about her.
Oh, come on...
Did she have any identifying features?
Something about her hair or her outfit?
About five years older than him, smooth hair,
eyes as red as rubies...
He was nine at the time, so if she was five years older...
Well, she'd be in her twenties now.
Smooth hair, red eyes... Who could that-
Top of the morning, ladies and gents!
Is something the matter?
Smooth hair...
Red eyes...
But she ain't twenty.
But she is a Humanoid!
Wh-What's all this about?
I have very important duties to attend to at Natsuki-san's side!
Please! Tell us the truth, okay?
You've met Natsu before, haven't you?
Natsuki-san?
Yeah! When he was still little!
I'm afraid any relevant memory data is still missing.
What? Really?
But these are my unbelievable specs we're talking about.
If there's any truth to this, you'd think I'd remem...
Piano?
Atri-chan!?
Atri-chan?
Thanks. I really oughta brush up on piano myself, huh?
Don't worry about it. This is the only song I can play, anyway.
Well, it's a good one.
Yeah. Someone precious to me really loved it.
Okay, class, put your desks back where they belong!
Time to get crackin'!
Where've you been?
Yes, ma'am!
Take your studies seriously, all right?
Natsuki-san...
Master's orders.
Natsu-kun!
Natsu-kun, your first crush...
Hey, you told them about that?
Oh, uh, funny story...
Do you think that girl might have been Atri?
Atri?
Come on, that's ridiculous!
But...
That girl was nothing like Atri.
She was more composed... Calm. Gentle.
The kind who wouldn't hesitate to reach out...
Come on. We've got class, too.
Bye!
I'll be back with dinner later!
They read books every day until nighttime, right?
They say it's 'cause they wanna be like Natsu.
They wanna go to the Academy one day.
Guess they don't care that I dropped out.
That doesn't matter! Be someone they can look up to.
Ririka needs a role model.
See you tomorrow.
Yeah.
You okay? You didn't even say goodbye.
It's nothing...
Natsuki-san.
I...
I...!
Atri!
It's been so long, Natsuki-san!