I-It hurts...
It hurts...
Help me...
I'm so cold...
I don't wanna die...
I'm scared...
Move! Move!
Mom?
Mom...
Not again.
Rise and shine, kiddo!
What are you doing here?
Oh, don't look at me like that.
You're talking to the lady
who's gonna make you rich.
Personal space.
If you're trying to seduce me,
you're wasting your time.
Please. You know you like it.
This one won't let you down, trust me.
Got it from a reliable seller.
Says it's as good as new.
How many times have I heard that before?
Keep writing checks like that,
and your death won't be pretty.
Just give it a try already!
You never know! You never know!
Here.
Well, it is better than
anything else you've brought me.
What'd I tell you?!
Guess I can at least give it a shot.
Not like we've got anything to lose.
Not when the world's like this.
...expected to serve as humanity's new
sustainable energy source, the Amaterasu Project
has been met with increasingly strong
opposition by local populations
as it prepares for its first stage of rocket launches...
Think it'll get off the ground this time?
It will.
But if they've got time to waste launching fireworks,
don'tcha figure they could do something
to actually make our lives better?
Even if we can scrape by for now,
things'll fall apart eventually.
We have to build a lasting future.
Man, this thing sure has seen better days.
You sure this piece of junk won't just sink?
You're the one who came up with this plan, granny.
Catherine!
Call me granny again and you'll be sleeping with the fishes!
Catherine isn't even your real name, is it?
What's the difference?
I don't wanna hear it!
It's a long and complicated story, okay?
Natsu!
Natsu! Ready for school?
Visitor for you, kid.
Just ignore her. She'll give up sooner or later.
Swing and a miss. If you wanna get your man,
you gotta know when to pull back.
I-It's not like that!
Just when I thought you'd finally stopped showing up...
Jesus, what am I, a black cat?
I'm Ikaruga Natsuki's one and only partner!
Hwuh?!
Partner?!
Quit making stuff up.
You're a con artist peddling a get-rich-quick scheme.
It's not a scheme! It's for real!
I happen to know for a fact that there's
treasure hidden in your old granny's house!
Your grandma?
The whatever-ologist?
Doctor Yachigusa Nonko the submarine geologist, yeah.
Catherine wants to salvage her house for sunken treasure
and split the profit.
That does sound fishy...
Oh, shut up!
So you ready, or what?
Yeah.
As long as there's nothing wrong with that spare part.
Really?!
W-Wait, you're going underwater in that?
Uh-huh.
I really don't think that's a good idea!
Your life is more precious than that!
Listen, kid. This is none of your business.
We both need cash, and we need it bad.
It's a harsh world we live in, after all!
Are you sure about this?
What if you find the treasure,
and she just thanks you for your service
before abandoning you in the middle of the ocean?
Wouldn't put it past her.
Are you serious?!
Don't say something so scary!
If you're that worried, you can just come with me.
Huh?
It's been years since this thing's gone underwater.
We could use an extra pair of hands.
Mhm...
That's no fair.
What?
Nothing.
Sea levels began rapidly rising all over the world.
Entire cities in low-lying areas
were inundated in the blink of an eye.
To this day, we don't know what caused it.
Experts have put forth plenty of theories;
an expansion in seawater volume due to global warming,
tectonic shifts raising the seafloor,
but none of them have been confirmed.
Once the sea level went up, it never went back down.
We lost cities and infrastructure en masse,
and the ocean is still slowly
but surely gobbling up more land.
Oh, um...
Once I get in and close the hatch,
release the hook for me.
Hook?
Th-This lever right here?
Catherine, you're in charge of the crane.
Ignition...
It's working!
Are we sure it's okay?
Let him go already! Fuel doesn't grow on trees!
Ugh!
Venting ballast tanks...
I really don't think you should go through with this!
The place I'm going is pretty shallow,
and I know exactly where it is. I'll be fine.
Besides, I owe it to myself to go at least once.
Huh?
Someone has to,
or it'll stay lost at the bottom of the sea forever.
We all used to live in this town...
Natsu...
There it is.
Unbelievable...
It looks just like it always did.
Natsu-kun, where are you?
Better catch me if you can, Minamo!
See ya!
Natsu-kun! Wait for me!
Find it yet?
Oh.
Yeah.
Here it is.
What's this?
What is it? A stash of gold ingots?
Yeah, right.
We're not dealing with a sunken pirate ship.
A capsule? Wait...
It's a girl.
A mannequin?
No... a Humanoid...
I'm sending it up.
Lower me the crane hook.
Sure thing.
She doesn't look the least bit artificial.
I've never seen such an intricately made model before...
Natsu! Natsu, what happened?
Not again...
Not again!
Natsu! Natsu!
"Atri"?
Raise the winch.
Huh?
Hurry and raise the winch!
Natsu!
There she is.
A leg...
That's my prosthetic.
Guess this is it.
The light sure is pretty...
So...
So pretty...
A Humanoid?
You mean she's a robot?
I do indeed
belong to the class of precision instruments
you humans refer to as such,
but that colloquial term is rather broad and imprecise.
Wow...
I've never seen such a lifelike Humanoid before.
But of course!
I'm a super high-spec model!
Who'd've guessed that old bag
was hiding something like this?
Hyper-realistic Humanoids
went out of production a long time ago.
It'll fetch a pretty penny!
You're gonna sell her?!
Of course we're gonna sell it!
That's the whole reason we went salvaging.
But is that something you're just allowed to do?
It most certainly is not!
It is illegal to use me in a financial transaction
without the consent of my master!
Your master?
Doctor Yachigusa Nonko!
Your master...
she passed away last month.
Huh? Nonko's...
Oh.
Uh, um...
She's dead, huh?
How unfortunate. Rest in peace.
She's... taking this awfully well.
Of course she is.
Everything she says and does
is the output of some computer code.
So there you have it!
Your new master is this kiddo right here.
The good doctor's grandson.
You get to do what he says now.
Ooh...
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance, Mister Kiddo.
Is that a suitable term of address?
Or would you prefer Daddy? Young Master?
Dear Brother? I have plenty more in my database!
My name's not Kiddo.
It's Natsuki.
Ikaruga Natsuki.
Natsuki?
And what should I call you?
Would you like my serial number?
No, your name.
Do you have one?
Of course.
Atri.
My name is Atri!
A-T-R-I.
Atri!
Atri...
That's me!
To robots, being given a human name
is proof that you have been recognized as a living being.
A testament to my mind-bogglingly high specs!
Oh, but Natsuki is a perfectly fine name, too.
Is this thing seriously looking down on me?
Of course not. You're much taller than I am.
Guess you don't do sarcasm.
Was he making fun of me, by any chance?
Whatever you do, don't sell her
until I get back from school, okay?
I know.
I mean it!
I really, really mean it!
So, what's the plan?
Come on, like I can afford to keep a Humanoid around.
I have to do something about my leg, too.
That's what I wanna hear.
Atri.
Yes!
Come with me.
Are we going for a walk, Master?
You'll see.
Taking its sweet time, huh?
Sure it won't just run away?
She's a Humanoid.
She's not gonna go against her master's orders.
Is it really that exciting?
Yes.
Everything I see here is brand-new to me.
This place has changed quite a bit over the past few years.
How many years were you asleep?
Was I asleep for that long?
You don't even know that much?
No. My memory banks are totally empty.
Follow me.
Hey!
Pick any pair you like.
What? You're buying it shoes?
It'll help increase her sale value.
Wow...
What?
Oh, nothing.
This pair is the best size,
but this has the superior design.
We're burning daylight here.
Make an executive decision already.
What do you think?
They're a perfect fit!
You're that happy about some shoes?
Yes!
It means my master has given me
something to own for myself!
Is it strange for me to be happy?
No.
No, it's not strange.
You'd never be able to tell that thing
apart from an ordinary human.
That's probably why they stopped making them.
Are you all right?
My leg did come off back there...
And besides, this prosthetic's an old model anyway.
So it isn't high-spec at all, then.
Yup, pretty much.
Would you look at that...
A genuine Yamasaki Factory fourth generation unit.
That's two generations after this one here.
Only two?
The realism sure came a long way in only two generations.
Yeah. It was all over the news when they first came out.
But then they issued a recall.
A recall?
So, what's our quote?
Outta my way!
What'll it be?!
I've never seen so many zeroes!
And half of it's all mine!
I've won! I've won the biggest jackpot of my life!
They must've been pretty defective
to warrant a recall, right?
And she's still worth this much?
Collectors love these sorta things.
So you've settled on a satisfactory price?
All thanks to my high specs, naturally!
What next? I can start searching
for a buyer right away.
Of course! Get on it right—
Excuse me.
Huh?
Can I ask you to wait for a little while before you sell me?
My former master...
Rather, Nonko left me with an order.
Before I went to sleep.
I'd like to carry it out first!
An order from my grandma?
Oh, what is it?
It's...
lost data.
What?
Oh no! What was it?
Um, um...
You're a robot, and you forget things?
I'm designed to have human-like thought patterns.
I forget things, just like anyone else!
Aah, what was it?
Do you remember, Master?
Of course I don't remember.
Ugh, some use you are...
Now what do I do?
You can't be serious...
I can't believe I lost such important data.
Even though I have such high specs...
Think I'm starting to see why they got recalled.
Still can't believe we got such
a crazy price for this bucket of bolts.
Calling a robot a "bucket of bolts"
is a direct violation of the Robot Anti-Discrimination Act!
Take it back!
Where were you keeping that whistle?!
Just hurry up and remember that order already.
Looks like we've got no choice.
Guess I'll be holding on to this thing for tonight.
Huh?
What? Don't be stupid.
The master's the only person who can sell a robot, right?
If I leave it with you, you might just run off
in the middle of the night.
You wanna sell her?
You don't?
So what if it ends up remembering a dead master's orders?
Even if it does, I somehow doubt
it's capable of carrying them out.
Besides, don't you want a new leg?
Atri.
Yes?
Go with Catherine.
Yes, Master.
I'll let you know when we've found ourselves a buyer.
Okay.
Let's go.
Yes.
H-Hey.
Wait.
Wait!
Are you serious?!
You really get what you pay for, huh?!
Excuse me...
What?!
Oh shit!
Don't you dare die on me here, you oversized toaster!
Hey, wait!
Come back.
Come back...
Master...
Natsu...
You scraped your knee.
I'll get the first-aid kit.
Sorry, but I want to be alone right now.
Okay.
I send you all the way to the Academy,
and you come crawling back in that sorry state?
What a disgrace.
What else could I do?
I wasn't...
Move! Move!
No... No!
Atri...
Natsuki.
I'll be your leg, Master!