Natsuki-san...
Get your filthy hands...
off of Atri!
Stand down.
So you side with the Humanoid, do you?
Atri has a heart.
She has a heart just like any human!
Atri!
Natsuki-san...
Unbelievable.
What a truly wretched machine you are...
deceiving this poor boy to such an extent.
Natsu!
Professor Konishi was truly
a sinful man.
Nothing short of the devil could have ever wrought such a creation.
For you see...
if this unit hadn't perpetrated that tragedy, if it hadn't escaped justice...
both the professor and the factory would be alive and well.
But all because of this thing, this defective pile of scrap metal...
No.
A-Atri isn't...
Atri isn't defective...
You're incorrigible.
Stop it!
Natsuki-san has nothing to do with this!
Then what do you propose?
Did you see that, friends?
That was a clear act of violence!
This Humanoid, in contravention to the Three Laws, struck me!
This lowly manmade tool
struck a human!
And so the truth comes out!
This is more than I had even hoped for!
A robot has harmed a human!
The proof is incontrovertible!
This unit is defective!
It cannot be allowed to roam free!
Y-Yasuda-san!
S-Stay back!
Atri...
Natsuki-san...
Please decomission me.
Atri...
I'm defective.
I'm willing to hurt and injure people.
I'm a defective Humanoid.
You have to destroy me.
I'm sorry, Atri.
I said all those horrible things to you.
I just had to apologize, even if it meant running all the way here.
I was so,
so terrible to you.
I'm sorry.
If anyone's defective, it's me.
D-Don't say that...
You have nothing to apologize for...
Atri.
Yes?
You do have a heart.
That's an error.
Not a heart.
I... have nothing like that.
How can you say that?
How are you supposed to know that for sure?
Nobody knows what the heart is.
Heck, I also can't be sure where my heart is,
or if I even have one at all.
That's how it is to be human.
What are you feeling now?
Nothing.
You don't have to hold back.
You don't have to keep it bottled up.
Just let the emotions wash over you.
You remember now, right?
Everything.
She's crying...
Shiina...
That's her first master's name?
Yeah.
My mother.
Ah, yep.
That explains why you found her with your grandma's stuff.
Oh, look...
Yeah. Tear stains.
Huh?
Atri was crying, and she didn't even notice it herself.
But I thought she said she couldn't cry...
She was making assumptions.
She thought Humanoids couldn't cry.
That they couldn't shed tears.
That they had no heart, and no real emotions.
Oh...
But these tear stains clinched it for me.
She does have a heart.
She's been suffering since the moment she was born.
Not wanting to do the right thing,
doing what you know is the wrong thing...
She's been struggling to come to terms with these impulses born from the heart.
Are you awake?
Natsuki-san...
Is your arm okay? Try and move it a little.
Okay...
Yes, everything seems to be in order.
Phew, that's good.
Um...
You don't have to worry about Yasuda anymore.
Catherine and Ryuuji are heading to the mainland to talk to the police.
We can't get him for hurting a Humanoid,
but he did take kids hostage and point a gun at Ryuuji.
Oh...
Atri-chan...
Don't beat yourself up about it!
I enjoyed the show!
But...
[traumatized robot noises]
Sometimes we make mistakes.
We do things we shouldn't.
Say things we shouldn't.
That's why we're able to be happy, or sad, or angry.
I want to be with you
because
I love you.
Natsuki-san...
That's the heart.
You can tell, right?
Yes!
The key is to keep your heart under control.
Control your emotions.
You can figure that out as you go.
Yeah!
Not all humans are great at it, anyway!
Yeah.
You might get some flak because you're a Humanoid,
but I'll be there for you every step of the way.
Um...
What's up?
For some reason, I have this incredible urge to hug you.
May I?
Yeah.
Is this a mistake?
Dunno.
But that's how it goes with the heart.
Think we should make like a tree and leaf?
I don't think it's like that.
Huh?
I think their bond is something else.
Something much deeper.
Atri?
Hey. Atri?
Maybe she's tired?
Well, she was definitely consuming a lot more power than normal.
She was?
I think she was reading her logs before she went to school yesterday.
She was reflecting on what she is,
what happened to her,
and the memories flooded back into her head.
All that happiness and sadness.
All at once.
Shiina-sama...
Opened my eyes.
Owner spoke to me.
I'm a busy woman.
You look after my daughter for me.
Wow! You're the Humanoid?
Yes.
Let's be friends!
It is a pleasure to make your acquaintance.
My name's Shiina. What's yours?
I do not have one. Call me however you wish.
I get to name you?
Uh, okay!
Ruri... Natsumi...
Oh, I know! Betty Beep-Boop!
"Betty Beep-Boop" is a derogatory slur.
Aw, but it's so cute...
Um, hmm...
Atri.
That's a migratory bird called an "atori."
So you can be Atri!
What do you think? Great name, right?
Atri...
That was what she named me.
"Atri."
Under my newfound name,
I began to live with Shiina-sama.
Ah.
Are you okay?
Shiina-sama...
You'll get the hang of it.
You're high-spec.
High-spec?
Yeah.
Mom says you're the latest high-spec model.
She said I'm in good hands.
Really?
Mom always says words have power.
So you should always say good things and never say bad things.
I think you should try and say it for yourself.
Go, "I'm high-spec!"
I'm high-spec.
Yeah! One more time!
I'm high-spec!
Yeah!
I'm high-spec, baby!
Shiina-sama's household was almost entirely just the two of us.
Aw, at least go a little easy on me!
Why are you so frightened by this particular bug?
Just kill it!
Why bother making this yourself?
It would be faster to just buy one.
No, no, baking it together makes for a better memory!
But she seems as content as ever.
All is well.
Today is Shiina-sama's first day of middle school.
I've confirmed distinct changes in her resulting from that fact.
What do you think, Atri?
How do I look?
Excellent.
But according to this photo,
everyone wears the same uniform.
I don't know how I'll be able to pick you out from the crowd.
Then if we ever can't find each other, how about we sing?
Remember that song I taught you?
Yeah, that's it!
Yes.
We're about the same height now, huh?
I guess now I'm gonna be the bigger kid...
That was the last time I saw Shiina-sama smile.
According to the report filed by the school, it started with something inconsequential.
Shiina-sama reproached another girl for talking during class.
It is assumed that the girl in question nursed a grudge over this.
She held authority within the school,
and thus many people became complicit in her hatred.
It was judged to be a case of a societal issue called "bullying."
I told you not to move it!
My apologies.
I'm sorry...
Stress levels rising.
Today makes three months of stress in the red zone.
She is in danger.
What?
You should talk to Nonko.
Mom's busy.
But...
She says the sea levels are rising,
and humanity's gonna be in trouble.
Not that anyone in the lab believes her.
Mom's gone nuts.
Take that back.
Words have power.
If you don't mean-
Shut up!
All you have to do is sit here and twiddle your thumbs.
What would you know!?
I'm sorry.
Do you have any idea how I feel?
Of course not.
You're a Humanoid.
You don't even have feelings.
No.
Stress levels continue to rise.
Something must be done.
I have to do something.
Anything!
At school, the class chose the lead actor for its play at the school festival.
I hypothesize that she was chosen for the role against her will.
I heard she's about to jump off the roof!
For real?
Yeah, it's hilarious!
Don't do anything stupid!
That's right, Yachigusa-san! Let's all calm down!
We all know you don't have the guts.
Hey!
If you really wanna die, why don't you prove it?
Then you won't have to be in the play.
Go on, jump.
Jump off!
Jump off! Jump off! Jump off!
If she jumps, she has a 97% chance of death.
Danger.
Danger!
I have to stop this.
Jump off!
The next thing I knew,
Who asked you to do this?
Shiina-sama-
You
monster.
I... I don't know what to say.
But despite all that, Atri still loved Shiina.
She wanted to be of use to her.
And that's why she escaped when they took her away.
Yeah.
And then she stayed out of sight
and watched over Mom in secret.
Even after Mom graduated, grew up, and had me...
Atri
was always...
always...
always there for her.
And I'm guessing Grandma found her,
erased her memories,
and put her to sleep.
[MISSING]
How are you feeling?
I had a dream.
Whew...
Um, may I ask you something?
I thought it'd look a little different now,
but it hasn't changed a bit, huh?
That's where I was watching you from.
You were, huh?
At the time, I was contemplating shutting down in this spot.
Just like you were.
I failed to save my dear Shiina-sama.
But...
At the time, you never once smiled.
So I employed the song and words Shiina-sama taught me.
There, there.
Everything's okay.
Thanks.
Huh?
I'm sure Mom's grateful, too.
You think so?
Yeah.
She was always talking about
how there was someone she needed to apologize to.
She was my best friend.
I loved her more than anyone in the world,
but I said some horrible things to her.
I hurt her.
I hope I can see her again someday.
I miss her.
Shiina-sama...
Yeah.
For the longest time, I never knew who she was talking about,
but now I'm certain it's you.
You were her best friend in the whole world.
Shiina-sama...
Oh.
I didn't want to be comforted...
I wanted to be someone who comforts people...
with these very words.
There, there.
Everything's okay.
Welcome home, Atri.