Eventually, the Rain Lets Up
Tuesday, overcast, 24°C
This morning, my owner Yachigusa Nonko initiated a
conversation with Shiina-sama.
A highly uncommon occurrence.
Learned that in addition to being my owner, she is also
Shiina-sama's biological mother.
Observed facts regarding the Yachigusa household
do not align with standard mental model of parenthood.
Nonko regularly spends all waking hours shut away in
her laboratory. Speculated to be engaged in unknown
scientific research.
Still have yet to register Shiina-sama's father in
image database. Inferred that he is similarly occupied
with research.
Was further asked to explain my reasoning.
Replied that I loved him in a romantic way.
Asserted that such feeling come from the heart.
Natsuki-san displayed no further signs of doubt.
Proceeded to bathe and commence nighttime
routine. No other notable occurrences.
I don't understand
I do not comprehend
31 YEARS AGO
NO ONE
LIKES YOU
GINKO JUNIOR HIGH SCHOOL