How did it come to this?
In that moment, all I wanted was to hold her close.
This tiny little Humanoid felt
right at home right there in my arms.
Like she was the most precious thing in the world...
Calm down! Calm down, dammit!
This is Atri we're talking about!
The dictionary definition of hardware failure!
Natsuki, do it right...
My back teeth won't brush themselves...
It's temporary insanity. It's gotta be!
Hey.
Hey! Wake up, Atri!
You have to reach waaay back...
What the heck kind of dream are you having?
Actually, wait...
You have dreams?
Natsuki, you dirty boy...
Sensei, I solved it...
Sensei?
Well, it is awfully hot today.
Yeah, totally...
like that explains anything!
It doesn't?
Something happened, that's for sure.
You think so?
Us girls know how to keep things zipped up,
but guys are an open book when they get like this!
Really?
Yup. And don't you forget it.
Ain't no guy in the world who can
pull the wool over a woman's eyes!
Have fun, kiddos!
But don't swim too far out, you hear?
Sensei! Atrin went under and isn't coming back up!
What?!
I found a crab!
That's a hermit crab...
Man, he's really got it bad.
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Something happen, buddy?
With a certain Atri, perhaps?
N-No.
Whoa, your ears are burning up!
Aren't you just too precious!
For real?
So you finally got over your denial
that Atri was your first love?
I...
Well?
"Well" what?
Did you maybe, just maybe,
take your relationship to the next level?
Get back here, Natsu.
It's got nothing to do with you guys.
Sure it does, right?
Huh?
You heard him.
Stop dragging this out and spill it already.
I told you already. Nothing happened, okay?
Go find something else to gossip about.
But—
Let's just drop it, all right?
He said nothing happened.
Sorry, Natsu. How 'bout we all
go join the kids for a swim?
Fine, I give up.
Huh?
And here I was trying to forget all about it...
I'll tell you, but don't get the wrong idea about it.
You kissed?!
You were the ones who asked!
I mean, yeah, but still...
Hell yeah, Natsu! I always knew you had it in you!
Knock it off!
C'mon, don't be shy!
Getting together with your first love?
That's every guy's dream, dude!
I told you not to get the wrong idea!
What's the big deal?
Bruhhhhh...
Hm?
That's a yikes from me...
Huh?
You heard me!
How old do you think this guy is, anyway?
Dude's seventeen!
And he wants to get with Atri?
That's gotta be statutor—
What part of "it's not like that" do you not understand?!
But you kissed her, didn't you?
That was, uh... a coincidence?
Or maybe a case of temporary insanity...
Yeah, tell it to the judge, buddy.
What do you even want from me?
Stop overreacting and just think about it!
Atri's a Humanoid. You shouldn't
think of her like an ordinary human.
But you were the one who said
she might have a heart.
And if that's true, she deserves
to be treated like the rest of us...
Well... yeah.
Either way, the elephant in the room you've
been avoiding is how you actually feel about her!
Well? You love her or not?
I ain't hearing a "no" from you.
To be honest... I'm not sure.
You're not sure?
In my mind, Atri's a Humanoid...
but she's also my first love...
It's all so confusing, I don't know
how to make sense of it all.
Oh...
Well, now that you put it that way,
I can get where you're coming from.
Until the other day, she was
just some random Humanoid,
but then it suddenly turns out
that she's your long-lost crush?
There you are!
Natsuki!
What?
Catherine said sneaking out of class is bad!
We're all supposed to be swimming right now!
You know I can't swim.
Catherine said there are ways
to practice swimming, even with a prosthetic!
My high specs will provide
all the assistance you need!
Taking a dip with a toaster like you? Count me out.
I value my life far too highly.
Officers! Take this man away!
Ahh, where's my whistle?!
Heh, figures. My calculator
probably has more RAM than you do.
Argh, that's that last straw!
Taste my super roundhouse rocket punch!
Oh, a new move? Go on,
hit me with your best shot!
Super roundhouse rocket—
Bye-bye!
See you tomorrow!
Talk about anything interesting today?
Yes. I learned about the theory of relativity.
From Ririka?
She really means it, you know?
About attending the Academy one day,
and about setting the world right.
It really reminds me of you.
Oh, Atri.
Yes?
If you wanna go for it tonight,
you should probably head on back
and start prepping soon.
Huh? But...
Do as Minamo says.
All right.
Look forward to it, Natsuki!
I'll be giving you a taste of mom's cooking tonight!
Mom's cooking?
I taught her a new dish.
She's getting pretty good.
Looks like it, yeah.
She really wants you to be happy.
She says that would make her happy, too.
You know, I think you were right all along.
I think Atri really does have a heart.
I don't think an AI could possibly say
something with that much feeling behind it.
So you should be true to your own heart...
And make sure you let her know how you feel, okay?
I know you can do it!
Minamo...
I'm rooting for you, Natsu.
See you!
You sure about this?
Hm?
Sorry. We were eavesdropping.
You know you're shooting yourself in the foot, right?
Yeah.
Guess I am.
And you're okay with that?
When Natsu went to the Academy,
I didn't cry at all.
Good luck.
Thanks.
I knew I was going to miss him,
but it made me even happier knowing
he was taking a big step towards his dream.
As I watched him walk away,
I realized I also needed to do
everything I could, right here.
Natsu was so young
when he lost both his mom and his leg,
but he still studied so hard all on his own,
never losing sight of his dream
to get the world moving again.
I don't want to be with him...
I want to do my best alongside him.
But—
Quiet, you!
Now that he has Atri to be there for him,
it feels like Natsu is
finally finding his old self again.
Why don't we get something to eat?
Huh?
Ms. Catherine said she was gonna
eat with Ririka at the school.
Wanna drop in?
Yeah. I'd love to!
Oh, count me in too!
I don't think so, pal. No boys allowed!
Right?
Yeah!
Mom's cooking is served!
It's just regular nikujaga.
Minamo told me it tastes
just like her mom used to make!
It's good.
But of course it is!
It was prepared by my high specs!
Housework comes as easily as breathing for yours truly!
And I'm supposed to believe that?
Why, it's nothing but the truth!
While it took me 107 failed tries
to perfect my hamburg steak,
I was able to succeed this time
on the mere 74th attempt!
A truly high-spec performance,
if I do say so myself!
You screwed up that many times?
You have nothing to worry about!
Minamo worked her magic on my failures,
so they all went in our bellies instead of the trash!
Was it worth all that just to cook for me?
Yes!
Seeing you enjoy tasty things makes me happy!
Why's that?
Why? Hmm...
Because it means I'm being useful to you, I guess!
Why does being useful make you happy?
Mmm, well...
Uh, um...
Oh! I know!
It must be love!
Huh? Uh...
I get it now. It's because I love you!
And not just garden-variety love.
It's the romantic kind of love!
Sheesh,
way to make it sound like I dragged it out of you...
Is that a bad thing?
Well, no.
If you really meant it, at least...
I do mean it.
I love you, Natsuki.
I'm starving.
Plus the food's getting cold.
Nikujaga's better while it's still hot, yeah?
Of course!
This is tough...
Do I really love Atri in that way?
She's the same as she's always been,
but here I am, projecting
that girl from eight years ago onto her...
Actually, wait.
She is that girl.
So that means...
What are you muttering to yourself about?
Hey, what do you think you're...
You're the one who told me
to go and get ready for my bath.
O-Oh, right.
What is the matter?
Wh-What're you doing?!
Oops.
I never knew you could scream like that, Natsuki!
Y-You'd better cut that out right now, okay?!
Ooooops!
And now your face is all red!
You're giving me all the reactions that I wanted!
You're so cute that I can't
help but want to tease you.
Don't say... I didn't warn you...
Robot harassment, I say!
How dare you hit me,
knowing full well that I can't hit you back?!
Should've thought about that before
trying to sexually harass me, bolts for brains!
That's still no excuse for violence!
Hmph!
It was justified self-defense!
Hm?
Uh, what are those?
Catherine gave them to me.
She made it very clear to me
that I ought to put the "YES" side up.
That way, you would be very gentle with me.
Trust me... to be gentle...
Yes, "a perfect gentleman." Was she wrong?
Am I doing it right?
Hell if I know.
Huh? Wait, come back!
Natsuki...
Being true to my heart, huh?
Huh?
Get up for a second.
I have an idea.
There.
That should do it.
What's this?
Now the bed is...
You'll be sleeping on this side from now on.
Huh? Why?
This will only keep me away from you!
That's the plan.
Heck, this is how it should've been from the start.
Do you not like having me next to you?
Do you hate me now?
No. I actually like you quite a bit.
Or, well, I guess "treasure"
might be the word I'm looking for.
As of today, I've decided to start
seeing you as a Humanoid with a heart.
A real heart, capable of feeling hurt
just like any other human's.
And that's what brought this on?
Yeah.
The human heart is awfully
complex and subtle, you know.
It's not the sort of thing
anyone can understand easily.
Feelings like love and hate, especially.
Huh...
I'm guessing you don't actually
understand anything yet.
So for now, I just want you to experience
more of the joys and sorrows of life
so that your heart has time to grow.
Natsuki...
And maybe then,
once you finally understand love
and we can both honestly face our feelings,
then we can decide what comes next for us.
Um, I'm not sure I understand...
What exactly are we supposed to do from now on?
Well, to put it simply...
To put it simply?
Exactly what we've always done.
What're you looking at, huh?!
I'm a grown-up. Who gives a rip if I drink?
This is how Ms. Catherine gets when she's drunk?
Yeah, I forgot...
You know, I've been wondering, actually.
What country is she from, anyway?
Oh, she's Japanese.
Her real nameHanako—
Don't call me that!!
Don't push yourself too hard, okay, Ririka?
Push myself?
Nah, I'm just doing it 'cause it's fun.
Is it?
Yeah.
Everyone calls me a hard worker,
but I'm only doing it 'cause I wanna.
Huh, you don't say.
Guess it's all about the mindset, huh?
Mm-hmm.
That's what makes the heart so hard to understand.
This right here...
is gonna take some serious thought.
This feels strange.
Is this how people usually sleep?
I dunno.
Some people do, others probably don't.
It's complicated.
Complicated.
Yeah.
The human heart is complicated.
It's not as simple as just deciding
to always do the right thing.
We all make mistakes, whether we want to or not.
Making mistakes...
Do I really have a heart?
I honestly think so.
C'mon. Let's sleep.
Thank you.
When you said you treasure me,
it made me really happy.
Right back at you.
The only reason I'm alive
right now is because of you.
Back then,
why did you say what you did?
There, there.
It'll be all right.
Because...
It's what I was taught...
There, there. It'll be all right.
I-It hurts... It hurts...!
It's okay.
Everything'll be all right.
You aren't alone.
Atri...
We kissed...
Failed to generate naturalistic affect,
but compensated by imitating
previously-seen reference materials.
Natsuki displayed no signs
of having detected any abnormality.
Natsuki said he loves me,
so I reciprocated the sentiment.
However, his conception of "love"
differed substantially from my mental model.
Learned about romantic love.
Retrieved relevant reference materials.
What the...
Learned about kissing.
Learned about sexual intercourse.
Learned about courtship displays and
mating rituals for initiating intercourse.
Natsuki continues to suspect nothing.
Asserted that I do have a heart.
Natsuki...
Stay away.
Huh?
Stay away from me!