I...
won't go with you.
Atri...
Thank you for everything.
Don't let her fool you!
Grandma's just trying to use you to her own ends!
Besides, she could've just been making up
that three-day time limit!
But if she wasn't,
I would lose all my memories, wouldn't I?
You said it yourself, didn't you?
Everything Nonko does, she does for a reason.
I...
I don't want to lose my memories of you.
It's not that simple!
You're so much more than just a machine...
You're a Humanoid with a heart!
You have a consciousness! Emotions!
And this system won't cut them off.
You'll feel every second, every day,
every year after year pass you by,
all while you're trapped in there,
unable to do anything!
Do you have any idea how painful that'll be?!
You really care a lot about me, don't you?
Stop it!
Thank you.
You can't!
We have three days.
Give me time!
Hey! Natsu!
Natsu!
Atri?
They're all here...
Cool!
Wow!
Someone really built all this?
That's one huge door!
Let's get going.
Huh? Already?
Dude, it took us all night to find this place.
We know the location now.
We can come back whenever we want.
And besides...
What is it?
Never mind.
Let's just head back to the island.
There's something I need to look into.
A secret?
Yes.
Natsuki told me not to breathe a word
about it to anyone.
What the heck, man?
Seriously? Even after how much we've helped him?
Can't believe he still doesn't trust us...
It's not like that.
I'm sure he just doesn't want
to burden us with his problems.
Dude seriously needs to lighten up a little.
Lighting up the school's one thing,
but his attitude's still got a long way to go...
Unfortunately, that is all I can say.
Thank you so much for everything, everyone.
Oh, come on.
You think we're gonna let you
off the hook that easily?
Atri, you still take down logs, right?
Of course.
The first order I ever received
was to write them every day!
Great!
Hm?
You still think I'm a useless,
bumbling idiot, don't you?
When you can't do something on your own,
you gotta ask for help.
Look.
She's here to take you to the mainland.
You might find a solution over there, right?
Go save her, bro.
You guys found out?
You bet.
And so do they.
We'll research stuff on our end, too.
You've only got three days left!
You don't have any time to waste!
Thank you.
Atri.
Sit tight.
I'm gonna find a way to save you.
I'm sure you want to go with him,
but bear with it for now, okay?
Um...
Can we have a talk, just the two of us?
So? What's up?
You said I should be free, right?
That I'm allowed to do whatever I want?
Yeah.
In that case...
I've decided that what I really want
is to carry out Nonko's orders.
I know what I'm signing up for.
I'm sure it'll be just like you said.
But still, it's a way that I can be useful!
To you, to our friends, and hopefully
lots and lots of other people, too.
When Nonko said I could be of service
to humanity, it made me so happy.
It felt like my heart
was going to beat out of my chest!
When she said it was my purpose,
it felt like I'd finally found what I was looking for.
I want to make myself useful!
To Miss Shiina,
to Nonko,
to you,
to Minamo,
to Catherine,
to all our friends,
and to this beautiful world...
I'm sure this meaning was
what I was looking for all along.
And the only reason I think this way...
The reason I want to do
everything I can to be useful...
is because I have a heart.
This is the purpose I was born for,
something nobody else can do.
And I...
I want to see it through.
Atri...
Yes?
Go become Eden's administrator.
I will.
We gotta get your bedhead under control.
This feels so nice.
I can hardly contain my happiness!
Yeah?
Mom used to comb my hair like this all the time.
She did?
No wonder I'm feeling so happy!
It's not every day we get to have a party, after all.
We'd better get you all dolled up!
You sure those are the shoes you wanna wear?
Yes!
They're the ones you bought for me.
It's awfully dark here, though.
Happy birthday!
Happy birthday, Atri!
Birthday...
The YHN-04B series came out
thirty-three years ago in August.
Maybe not this exact day, but close enough.
Natsu looked it up. And so we figured
we might as well turn this into a birthday party!
A birthday party...
That's right!
Isn't that way too many candles?
There's exactly thirty-three!
We counted each one!
Missus Hana probably needs
that many on her cake!
Do not!
Time to blow 'em all out.
Me?
Happy birthday!
Alright everyone, smile for the camera!
Wow!
You look like a wizard!
Which one do you wanna try?
I've done this with Miss Shiina before.
Really?
I didn't understand what was so fun
about it back then, though.
Just give it a try and you'll see!
Pretty, isn't it?
Here go the rockets!
Whoa! Rockets!
So that's what a rocket is!
Well, rockets come in lots of shapes and sizes.
Oh, right. It's almost time, huh?
Yeah.
Atri...
Natsu.
This is a goodbye party for you, too, got it?
Don't be shy.
Nah, I'll pass. It's not really my thing.
Oh, stop it. You're the whole reason
we're all here in the first place.
Atri, gimme a hand!
Coming!
Okay, here goes.
Three, two, one...
It's so pretty!
Yeah.
I always thought
goodbyes were supposed to be sad.
And maybe they are...
But only because of all
the fun times we had together.
Yeah.
Sorry.
It was real mean of me not to let you in the school.
I know you were just doing it to protect everyone.
I'll get my butt on a rocket one day,
so you better work hard, too!
Yes!
I know we'll see each other again someday.
What she said.
You're a strong one.
Yes!
See ya!
Later.
Natsuki...
Hm?
Say no more.
I have a favor to ask of you, Minamo.
Once I'm gone, I want you to look after Natsuki.
Atri...
He's a big ol' baby, so he really needs
someone to be there for him.
Right...
Will you do that for me?
Nope, don't think I can.
Huh?
Natsu is a lot stronger now.
Plus, you and I both have so much left to do.
Even if we can't see each other anymore.
Minamo...
Even if we end up all alone,
we have to do whatever we can.
Stay strong, be brave.
And forge a path for ourselves.
Stay strong, be brave...
I just know it!
Whenever I feel like giving up, I'll always think of you,
and it'll help me get through it!
And I'm sure Natsu will do the same.
It's a promise!
Yes!
We're here.
I'm sorry for rushing you through things.
You sure about this?
You still have a whole day left.
Yes.
I wouldn't know how to spend it anyway.
Though I must say,
these shoes sure are hard to walk in...
Why not go with your usual pair then?
Perish the thought.
These are the ones I want to go to sleep in.
The ones that you bought for me.
Um, can I ask you for one last favor?
There, nice and clean!
The finest job I've done yet.
Now nobody will doubt me
if I tell them I'm a combat robot!
You know it!
You could call yourself humanity's ultimate weapon,
and everyone would believe you!
Then let me give you a present
to express my gratitude.
Huh?
What's this?
Everyone pitched in to buy it.
This way, you can keep moving forward,
no matter where you go.
What do you think?
It's light...
It's high-spec!
Though not as high-spec as yours truly, naturally.
Thank you.
I'm counting on you.
Please always be there for Natsuki.
Don't you worry about her.
She's all refurbished and
ready to serve me for years to come.
Let's both do our best, okay?
It's awfully quiet.
They're going to launch the rocket soon, right?
Yeah.
I would've loved to see it.
Atri.
Thank you for everything.
I don't know if this is the right thing to do,
but right now, I don't think I've ever been happier.
Miss Shiina, Nonko, you, Minamo, Ryuuji,
Ririka, Catherine, Youko, Tooru, Miyo...
I love each and every one of you so much.
So how can I not be
the happiest Humanoid in the world?
Don't leave me like this!
You're supposed to be my leg, aren't you?
You said you'd always support me, didn't you?
You said you'd...
be there for me...
So don't go...
Oh, what am I ever going to do with you?
Didn't you already decide
that you'd go back to the Academy?
Didn't you promise me
you'd keep trying your very best?
And when I told you this was what I wanted,
didn't you agree to support my decision?
That's only because... you were there for me...
And I still will be.
Right here...
with you.
Once you've accomplished everything you've wanted,
once you have no more regrets left,
please, come back and find me.
I'll save my very last day just for you!
Until then...
I'll be waiting.
Atri!
I still haven't—
Atri...
Atri!
What the...
I never knew the sea had so many stars in it.
You're the one who lit them up.
Really?
All I did was flip a switch.
I'll bet the town is going crazy right now.
I never knew...
I could also
cry tears of joy.
Watch me. I'll set time moving forward again.
I'll unpause humanity's progress
and finally set things to right.
Yes...
And then, I'll come back to you.
I swear it.
I believe you!
Because you're high-spec!
Today, as we celebrate the 70th anniversary
of the Amaterasu Project's first launch,
its first pilot, Nanami Ririka, will be able
to watch her granddaughter, Nanami Hana,
set off for the Amaterasu Space Station.
Their heroic efforts contributed to the reversal
of the catastrophic rising sea level crisis,
serving as a beacon of hope to humanity.
Dubbed "The Restarter of Progress"
alongside the resumption of Humanoid research,
today's rocket launch is set to propel
humanity to ever greater heights.
Oh, Granny Youko says she's watching, too! Let's go!
Can I?
I'm just a Humanoid...
Are you still living in the last century or what?
Granny Youko and Grandpa Ryuuji
couldn't care less about that!
Come on!
H-Hey!
From her very first day in office as mayor,
my grandmother Kamishiro Minamo
spared no effort in using Eden
to rebuild our town.
Since that humble beginning, the Eden Project
has spread all across the world,
serving a paramount role
in the recovery of our planet.
For that, I couldn't be more proud
to be her granddaughter.
Unfortunately, my grandmother
was unable to attend today's ceremony,
but please allow me to convey, on her behalf,
the enormous pride and joy she feels
to be granted the privilege of decommissioning the first
of now over 100 currently operational Eden facilities.
And now, let us commence
with the shutdown procedure.
Esteemed guests, please take
your position in front of the switch.
You may now cut the power.
Thank you for your service, Eden 1!
Atri.
Natsuki?
You awake?
Where am I?
Can't you tell?
This can't be right!
It's been seventy years!
You should be an old man by now!
Who says I'm not?
Long story short, this is a world of data.
I tried everything I could, but I just couldn't find
any way to get you out of that capsule.
That old bag was always five steps ahead...
Data?
So I had to settle for my plan B
and wait until Eden's end of service
so that I could extract your data from the system.
Then does that mean you're actually...
You know it.
But don'tcha think I look better as my old self
instead of some toothless geezer?
Let's go!
Go where?
Huh?!
Like I said, it's all just data.
So it's a piece of cake to reproduce
a replica of the real world.
It's nearly time...
T-minus five seconds.
Four.
Three.
Two.
One.
You wanted to see the rocket, didn't you?
Ririka's granddaughter is in there,
following in her grandma's footsteps.
Huh?
But what about you?
Oh, as if I had time for that.
I was too busy researching Humanoids.
Humanoids...
I'll have you know, they call me
the Father of Humanoid Rights.
Really?
You know it.
Because guess what?
I'm high-spec, baby!
Pfft, sure thing, gramps!
Hey, you were the one who said it first!
Besides, if we're playing the age card,
you're well over a hundred!
Who cares?
I'm a Humanoid, baby!
Here, none of that makes a difference.
We're ourselves, and that's all that matters.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
You might only have one day left...
But here, that day can last forever.
Where do you wanna go?
That hill by the sea.
That place Miss Shiina promised
she'd be waiting for me!
Yeah.
Let's go!