hatenai yoru wo koete
The clouded sea has naught a guiding star
kimi ga nemuru umi e kogidasuyo
Yet I row to your silent cradle every single night
namida ni
And there you sleep
shizumu aoi hoshi de hitori
Drifting through past a sunken, azure symphony
omoide
As the memories
tachi wa
Escape us
awa to
They surface
natte kierukedo
Blink and I can't recall your face
demo boku wa oboeteru
Then I close my eyes, and I think of you
namida ga kagayaku toki wo
The sparkle of your tears stirs every memory
wasurezu utauyo saa
I remember... Bursting into song!
ima hikari hanate
We cast our light across the seas
mirai no michishi
Paved a path among the stars
rube wo sora ni egake
For those who've yet to walk beside us
boku wa mou mayou
When I lost my way, you came
wanai sou kimetanda
And helped me find the wings to guide me
habatake
So I'll soar now
maasugu
Through azure blue
kimi no moto e
'Cross the world to see you